<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<pc version="5">
	<character>
		<name>Adeldian</name>
		<race>
			<id>11</id>
			<name>Half-Elf</name>
			<feat>
				<name>Darkvision</name>
				<text>Thanks to your elf blood, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Fey Ancestry</name>
				<text>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, and magic can't put you to sleep.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Languages</name>
				<text>Common, Elvish, and Sylvan.</text>
			</feat>
			<mod>
				<category>1</category>
				<type>5</type>
				<value>2</value>
			</mod>
			<mod>
				<category>1</category>
				<type>1</type>
				<value>1</value>
			</mod>
			<mod>
				<category>1</category>
				<type>4</type>
				<value>1</value>
			</mod>
			<proficiency>100</proficiency>
			<proficiency>116</proficiency>
		</race>
		<class>
			<id>7</id>
			<name>Druid</name>
			<level>6</level>
			<hd>2</hd>
			<hdCurrent>0</hdCurrent>
			<spellAbility>4</spellAbility>
			<slots>3,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			<slotsCurrent>3,1,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slotsCurrent>
			<spell>
				<name>Animal Friendship</name>
				<level>1</level>
				<school>4</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>30 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a morsel of food) </components>
				<duration>24 hours</duration>
				<text>This spell lets you convince a beast that you mean it no harm. Choose a beast that you can see within range. It must see and hear you. If the beast's Intelligence is 4 or higher, the spell fails. Otherwise, the beast must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be charmed by you for the spell's duration. If you or one of your companions harms the target, the spell ends. 
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a 2nd level spell slot or higher, you can affect one additional beast for each slot level above 1st.
	
	Charmed:
	• A charmed creature can't attack the charmer or target the charmer with harmful abilities or magical effects.
	
	• The charmer has advantage on any ability check to interact socially with the creature.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 212</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Animal Messenger</name>
				<level>2</level>
				<school>4</school>
				<ritual>1</ritual>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>30 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a morsel of food) </components>
				<duration>24 hours</duration>
				<text>By means of this spell, you use an animal to deliver a message. Choose a Tiny beast you can see within range, such as a squirrel, a blue ray, or a bird. You specify a location, which you must have visited, and a recipient who matches a general description, such as a man or woman dressed in the uniform of the town guard or a red-haired dwarf wearing a pointed hat. You also speak a message of up to twenty-five words. The target beast travels for the duration of the spell towards the specified location, covering about 50 miles per 24 hours for a flying messenger or 25 miles for other animals. 
	When the messenger arrives, it delivers your message to the creature that you described, replicating the sound of your voice. The messenger speaks only to a creature matching the description you gave. If the messenger doesn't reach its destination before the spell ends, the message is lost, and the beast makes it way back to where you cast this spell. 
	
	At Higher Levels: If you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the duration of the spell increases by 48 hours for each slot level above 2nd.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 212</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Animal Shapes</name>
				<level>8</level>
				<school>8</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>30 feet</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 24 hours</duration>
				<text>Your magic turns others into beasts. Choose any number of willing creatures that you can see within range. You transform each target into the form of a large or smaller beast with a challenge rating of 4 or lower. On subsequent turns, you can use your actions to transform affected creatures into new forms. 
	The transformation lasts for the duration for each target, or until the target drops to 0 hit points or dies. You can choose a different form for each target. A target's game statistics are replaced by the statistics of the chosen beast, though the target retains its alignment and Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma scores. The target assumes the hit points of its new form, and when it reverts to its normal form, it returns to the number of hit point it had before it transformed. If it reverts as a result of dropping to 0 hit points, any excess damage carries over to its normal form. As long as the excess damage doesn't reduce the creature's normal form to 0 hit points, it isn't knocked unconscious. The creature is limited in the actions it can perform by the nature of its new form, and it can't speak or cast spells. 
	The target's gear melds into the new form. The target can't activate, wield, or otherwise benefit from any of its equipment.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 212</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Antilife Shell</name>
				<level>5</level>
				<school>1</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self (10-foot radius)</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
				<text>A shimmering barrier extends out from you in a 10-foot radius and moves with you, remaining centered on you and hedging out creatures other than undead and constructs. 
	The barrier lasts for the duration. The barrier prevents an affected creature from passing or reaching through. An affected creature can cast spells or make attacks with ranged or reach weapons through the barrier. 
	If you move so that an affect creature is forced to pass through the barrier, the spell ends.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 213</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Antipathy/Sympathy</name>
				<level>8</level>
				<school>4</school>
				<time>1 hour</time>
				<range>60 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (either a lump of alum soaked in vinegar for the antipathy effect or a drop of honey for the sympathy effect)</components>
				<duration>10 days</duration>
				<text>This spell attracts or repels creatures of your choice. You target something within range, either a Huge or smaller object or creature or an area that is no larger than a 200-foot cube. Then specify a kind of intelligent creature, such as red dragons, goblins, or vampires. You invest the target with an aura that either attracts or repels the specified creatures for the duration. Choose antipathy or sympathy as the aura's effect.
	Antipathy: The enchantment causes creatures of the kind you designated to feel an intense urge to leave the area and avoid the target. When such a creature can see the target or comes within 60 feet of it, the creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become frightened. The creature remains frightened while it can see the target or is within 60 feet of it. While frightened by the target, the creature must use its movement to move to the nearest safe spot from which it can't see the target. If the creature moves more than 60 feet from the target and can't see it, the creature is no longer frightened, but the creature becomes frightened again if it regains sight of the target or moves within 60 feet of it.
	Sympathy: The enchantment causes the specified creatures to feel an intense urge to approach the target while within 60 feet of it or able to see it. When such a creature can see the target or comes within 60 feet of it, the creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or use its movement on each of its turns to enter the area or move within reach of the target. When the creature has done so, it can't willingly move away from the target. If the target damages or otherwise harms an affected creature, the affected creature can make a Wisdom saving throw to end the effect, as described below.
	Ending the Effect: If an affected creature ends its turn while not within 60 feet of the target or able to see it, the creature makes a Wisdom saving throw. On a successful save, the creature is no longer affected by the target and recognizes the feeling of repugnance or attraction as magical. In addition, a creature affected by the spells is allowed another Wisdom saving throw every 24 hours while the spell persists.
	A creature that successfully saves against this effect is immune to it for 1 minute, after which time it can be affected again.
	
	Frightened:
	• A frightened creature has disadvantage on ability checks and attack rolls while the source of its fear is within line of sight.
	
	• The creature can't willingly move closer to the source of its fear.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 214</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Awaken</name>
				<level>5</level>
				<school>8</school>
				<time>8 hours</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<components>V, S, M (an agate worth at least 1,000 gp, which the spell consumes)</components>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>After spending the casting time tracing magical pathways within a precious gemstone, you touch a huge or smaller beast or plant. The target must have either no Intelligence score or an Intelligence of 3 or less. The target gains an Intelligence of 10. The target also gains the ability to speak one language you know. If the target is a plant, it gains the ability to move its limbs, roots, vines, creepers, and so forth, and it gains senses similar to a human's. Your DM chooses statistics appropriate for the awakened plant, such as the statistics for the awakened shrub or the awakened tree. 
	The awakened beast or plant is charmed by you for 30 days or until you and your companions do anything harmful to it. When the charmed condition ends, the awakened creature chooses whether to remain friendly to you, based on how you treated it while it was charmed.
	
	Charmed:
	• A charmed creature can't attack the charmer or target the charmer with harmful abilities or magical effects.
	
	• The charmer has advantage on any ability check to interact socially with the creature.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 216</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Barkskin</name>
				<level>2</level>
				<school>8</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a handful of oak bark)</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
				<text>You touch a willing creature. Until the spell ends, the target's skin has a rough, bark-like appearance, and the target's AC can't be less than 16, regardless of what kind of armor it is wearing.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 217</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Beast Sense</name>
				<level>2</level>
				<school>3</school>
				<ritual>1</ritual>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<components>S</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
				<text>You touch a willing beast. For the duration of the spell, you can use your action to see through the beast's eyes and hear what it hears, and continue to do so until you use your action to return to your normal senses.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 217</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Blight</name>
				<level>4</level>
				<school>7</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>30 feet</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>Necromantic energy washes over a creature of your choice that you can see within range, draining moisture and vitality from it. The target must make a Constitution saving throw. The target takes 8d8 necrotic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs. 
	If you target a plant creature or a magical plant, it makes the saving throw with disadvantage, and the spell deals maximum damage to it. 
	If you target a nonmagical plant that isn't a creature, such as a tree or shrub, it doesn't make a saving throw, it simply withers and dies. 
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 4th.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 219</text>
				<roll>8d8</roll>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Warlock</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Call Lightning</name>
				<level>3</level>
				<school>2</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>120 feet</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
				<text>A storm cloud appears in the shape of a cylinder that is 10 feet tall with a 60-foot radius, centered on a point you can see 100 feet directly above you. The spell fails if you can't see a point in the air where the storm cloud could appear (for example, if you are in a room that can't accommodate the cloud). 
	When you cast the spell, choose a point you can see within range. A bolt of lightning flashes down from the cloud to that point. Each creature within 5 feet of that point must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 3d10 lightning damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. On each of your turns until the spell ends, you can use your action to call down lightning in this way again, targeting the same point or a different one. 
	If you are outdoors in stormy conditions when you cast this spell, the spell gives you control over the existing storm instead of creating a new one. Under such conditions, the spell's damage increases by 1d10. 
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher level, the damage increases by 1d10 for each slot level above 3rd. 

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 220</text>
				<prepared>1</prepared>
				<roll>3d10</roll>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Charm Person</name>
				<level>1</level>
				<school>4</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>30 feet</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>1 hour</duration>
				<text>You attempt to charm a humanoid you can see within range. It must make a Wisdom saving throw, and does so with advantage if you or your companions are fighting it. If it fails the saving throw, it is charmed by you until the spell ends or until you or your companions do anything harmful to it. The charmed creature regards you as a friendly acquaintance. When the spell ends, the creature knows it was charmed by you. 
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 1st. The creatures must be within 30 feet of each other when you target them.
	
	Charmed:
	• A charmed creature can't attack the charmer or target the charmer with harmful abilities or magical effects.
	
	• The charmer has advantage on any ability check to interact socially with the creature.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 221</text>
				<sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Warlock</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Commune with Nature</name>
				<level>5</level>
				<school>3</school>
				<ritual>1</ritual>
				<time>1 minute</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>You briefly become one with nature and gain knowledge of the surrounding territory. In the outdoors, the spell gives you knowledge of the land within 3 miles of you. In caves and other natural underground settings, the radius is limited to 300 feet. The spell doesn't function where nature has been replaced by construction, such as in dungeons and towns. 
	You instantly gain knowledge of up to three facts of your choice about any of the following subjects as they relate to the area: 
	• terrain and bodies of water
	• prevalent plants, minerals, animals, or peoples
	• powerful celestials, fey, fiends, elementals, or undead
	• influence from other planes of existence
	• buildings 
	For example, you could determine the location of powerful undead in the area, the location of major sources of safe drinking water, and the location of any nearby towns.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 224</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Confusion</name>
				<level>4</level>
				<school>4</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>90 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (three nut shells)</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>This spell assaults and twists creatures' minds, spawning delusions and provoking uncontrolled actions. Each creature in a 10-foot-radius sphere centered on a point you choose within range must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw when you cast this spell or be affected by it. 
	An affected target can't take reactions and must roll a d10 at the start of each of its turns to determine its behavior for that turn. 
	1 — The creature uses all its movement to move in a random direction. To determine the direction, roll a d8 and assign a direction to each die face. The creature doesn't take an action this turn. 
	2-6 — The creature doesn't move or take actions this turn. 
	7-8 — The creature uses its action to make a melee attack against a randomly determined creature within its reach. If there is no creature within its reach, the creature does nothing this turn. 
	9-10 — The creature can act and move normally. 
	At the end of its turns, an affected target can make a Wisdom saving throw. If it succeeds, this effect ends for that target. 
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the radius of the sphere increases by 5 feet for each slot above 4th. 

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 224</text>
				<sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Conjure Animals</name>
				<level>3</level>
				<school>2</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>60 feet</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
				<text>You summon fey spirits that take the form of beasts and appear in unoccupied spaces that you can see within range. Choose one of the following options for what appears: 
	• One beast of challenge rating 2 or lower 
	• Two beasts of challenge rating 1 or lower 
	• Four beasts of challenge rating 1/2 or lower 
	• Eight beasts of challenge rating 1/4 or lower 
	Each beast is also considered fey, and it disappears when it drops to 0 hit points or when the spell ends. 
	The summoned creatures are friendly to you and your companions. Roll initiative for the summoned creatures as a group, which has its own turns. They obey any verbal commands that you issue to them (no action required by you). If you don't issue any commands to them, they defend themselves from hostile creatures, but otherwise take no actions. The DM has the creatures' statistics. 
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using certain higher-level spell slots, you choose one of the summoning options above, and more creatures appear: twice as many with a 5th-level slot, three times as many with a 7th-level slot, and four times as many with a 9th-level slot.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 225</text>
				<prepared>1</prepared>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Conjure Elemental</name>
				<level>5</level>
				<school>2</school>
				<time>1 minute</time>
				<range>90 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (burning incense for air, soft clay for earth, sulfur and phosphorus for fire, or water and sand for water)</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
				<text>You call forth an elemental servant. Choose an area of air, earth, fire, or water that fills a 10-foot cube within range. An elemental of challenge rating 5 or lower appropriate to the area you chose appears in an unoccupied space within 10 feet of it. For example, a fire elemental emerges from a bonfire, and an earth elemental rises up from the ground. The elemental disappears when it drops to 0 hit points or when the spell ends. 
	The elemental is friendly to you and your companions for the duration. Roll initiative for the elemental, which has its own turns. It obeys any verbal commands that you issue to it (no action required by you). If you don't issue any commands to the elemental, it defends itself from hostile creatures but otherwise takes no actions. 
	If your concentration is broken, the elemental doesn't disappear. Instead, you lose control of the elemental, it becomes hostile toward you and your companions, and it might attack. An uncontrolled elemental can't be dismissed by you, and it disappears 1 hour after you summoned it. The DM has the elemental's statistics. 
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the challenge rating increases by 1 for each slot level above 5th.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 225</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Conjure Fey</name>
				<level>6</level>
				<school>2</school>
				<time>1 minute</time>
				<range>90 feet</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
				<text>You summon a fey creature of challenge rating 6 or lower, or a fey spirit that takes the form of a beast of challenge rating 6 or lower. It appears in an unoccupied space that you can see within range. The fey creature disappears when it drops to 0 hit points or when the spell ends. 
	The fey creature is friendly to you and your companions for the duration. Roll initiative for the creature, which has its own turns. It obeys any verbal commands that you issue to it (no action required by you), as long as they don't violate its alignment. If you don't issue any commands to the fey creature, it defends itself from hostile creatures but otherwise takes no actions.
	If your concentration is broken, the fey creature doesn't disappear. Instead, you lose control of the fey creature, it becomes hostile toward you and your companions, and it might attack. An uncontrolled fey creature can't be dismissed by you, and it disappears 1 hour after you summoned it. The DM has the fey creature's statistics. 
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 7th level or higher, the challenge rating increases by 1 for each slot level above 6th.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 226</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Warlock</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Conjure Minor Elementals</name>
				<level>4</level>
				<school>2</school>
				<time>1 minute</time>
				<range>90 feet</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
				<text>You summon elementals that appear in unoccupied spaces that you can see within range. You choose one the following options for what appears: .
	• One elemental of challenge rating 2 or lower
	• Two elementals of challenge rating 1 or lower 
	• Four elementals of challenge rating 1/2 or lower 
	• Eight elementals of challenge rating 1/4 or lower. 
	An elemental summoned by this spell disappears when it drops to 0 hit points or when the spell ends. 
	The summoned creatures are friendly to you and your companions. Roll initiative for the summoned creatures as a group, which has its own turns. They obey any verbal commands that you issue to them (no action required by you). If you don't issue any commands to them, they defend themselves from hostile creatures, but otherwise take no actions. The DM has the creatures' statistics. 
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using certain higher-level spell slots, you choose one of the summoning options above, and more creatures appear: twice as many with a 6th-level slot and three times as many with an 8th-level slot

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 226</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Conjure Woodland Beings</name>
				<level>4</level>
				<school>2</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>60 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (one holly berry per creature summoned)</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
				<text>You summon fey creatures that appear in unoccupied spaces that you can see within range. Choose one of the following options for what appears: 
	• One fey creature of challenge rating 2 or lower 
	• Two fey creatures of challenge rating 1 or lower 
	• Four fey creatures of challenge rating 1/2 or lower 
	• Eight fey creatures of challenge rating 1/4 or lower
	A summoned creature disappears when it drops to 0 hit points or when the spell ends. The summoned creatures are friendly to you and your companions. Roll initiative for the summoned creatures as a group, which have their own turns. They obey any verbal commands that you issue to them (no action required by you). If you don't issue any commands to them, they defend themselves from hostile creatures, but otherwise take no actions. The DM has the creatures' statistics. 
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using certain higher-level spell slots, you choose one of the summoning options above, and more creatures appear: twice as many with a 6th-level slot and three times as many with an 8th-level slot.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 226</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Contagion</name>
				<level>5</level>
				<school>7</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>7 days</duration>
				<text>Your touch inflicts disease. Make a melee spell attack against a creature within your reach. On a hit, you afflict the creature with a disease of your choice from any of the ones described below. 
	At the end of each of the target's turns, it must make a Constitution saving throw. After failing three of these saving throws, the disease's effects last for the duration, and the creature stops making these saves. After succeeding on three of these saving throws, the creature recovers from the disease, and the spell ends. 
	Since this spell induces a natural disease in its target, any effect that removes a disease or otherwise ameliorates a disease's effects apply to it. 
	Blinding Sickness: Pain grips the creature's mind, and its eyes turn milky white. The creature has disadvantage on Wisdom checks and Wisdom saving throws and is blinded. 
	Filth Fever: A raging fever sweeps through the creature's body. The creature has disadvantage on Strength checks, Strength saving throws, and attack rolls that use Strength. 
	Flesh Rot: The creature's flesh decays. The creature has disadvantage on Charisma checks and vulnerability to all damage. 
	Mindfire: The creature's mind becomes feverish. The creature has disadvantage on Intelligence checks and Intelligence saving throws, and the creature behaves as if under the effects of the confusion spell during combat. 
	Seizure: The creature is overcome with shaking. The creature has disadvantage on Dexterity checks, Dexterity saving throws, and attack rolls that use Dexterity. 
	Slimy Doom: The creature begins to bleed uncontrollably. The creature has disadvantage on Constitution checks and Constitution saving throws. In addition, whenever the creature takes damage, it is stunned until the end of its next turn. 
	
	Blinded:
	• A blinded creature can't see and automatically fails any ability check that requires sight.
	
	• Attack rolls against the creature have advantage, and the creature's attack rolls have disadvantage.
	
	Stunned:
	• A stunned creature is incapacitated, meaning it can't take actions or reactions, can't move, and can speak only falteringly.
	
	• The creature automatically fails Strength and Dexterity saving throws.
	
	• Attack rolls against the creature have advantage.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 227</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Control Water</name>
				<level>4</level>
				<school>8</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>300 feet</range>
				<components>V, S , M (a drop of water and a pinch of dust)</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
				<text>Until the spell ends, you control any freestanding water inside an area you choose that is a cube up to 100 feet on a side. You can choose from any of the following effects when you cast this spell. As an action on your turn, you can repeat the same effect or choose a different one. 
	Flood: You cause the water level of all standing water in the area to rise by as much as 20 feet. If the area includes a shore, the flooding water spills over onto dry land. If you choose an area in a large body of water, you instead create a 20-foot tall wave that travels from one side of the area to the other and then crashes down. Any Huge or smaller vehicles in the wave's path are carried with it to the other side. Any Huge or smaller vehicles struck by the wave have a 25 percent chance of capsizing. The water level remains elevated until the spell ends or you choose a different effect. If this effect produced a wave, the wave repeats on the start of your next turn while the flood effect lasts. 
	Part Water: You cause water in the area to move apart and create a trench. The trench extends across the spell's area, and the separated water forms a wall to either side. The trench remains until the spell ends or you choose a different effect. The water then slowly fills in the trench over the course of the next round until the normal water level is restored. 
	Redirect Flow: You cause flowing water in the area to move in a direction you choose, even if the water has to flow over obstacles, up walls, or in other unlikely directions. The water in the area moves as you direct it, but once it moves beyond the spell's area, it resumes its flow based on the terrain conditions. The water continues to move in the direction you chose until the spell ends or you choose a different effect. 
	Whirlpool: This effect requires a body of water at least 50 feet square and 25 feet deep. You cause a whirlpool to form in the center of the area. The whirlpool forms a vortex that is 5 feet wide at the base, up to 50 feet wide at the top, and 25 feet tall. Any creature or object in the water and within 25 feet of the vortex is pulled 10 feet toward it. A creature can swim away from the vortex by making a Strength (Athletics) check against your spell save DC. When a creature enters the vortex for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, it must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, the creature takes 2d8 bludgeoning damage and is caught in the vortex until the spell ends. On a successful save, the creature takes half damage, and isn't caught in the vortex. A creature caught in the vortex can use its action to try to swim away from the vortex as described above, but has disadvantage on the Strength (Athletics) check to do so. The first time each turn that an object enters the vortex, the object takes 2d8 bludgeoning damage, this damage occurs each round it remains in the vortex. 

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 227</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Control Weather</name>
				<level>8</level>
				<school>8</school>
				<time>10 minutes</time>
				<range>Self (5-mile radius)</range>
				<components>V, S, M (burning incense and bits of earth and wood mixed in water)</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 8 hours</duration>
				<text>You take control of the weather within 5 miles of you for the duration. You must be outdoors to cast this spell. Moving to a place where you don't have a clear path to the sky ends the spell early. 
	When you cast the spell, you change the current weather conditions, which are determined by the DM based on the climate and season. You can change precipitation, temperature, and wind. It takes 1d4 x 10 minutes for the new conditions to take effect. Once they do so, you can change the conditions again. When the spell ends, the weather gradually returns to normal. 
	When you change the weather conditions, find a current condition on the following tables and change its stage by one, up or down. When changing the wind, you can change its direction. 
	
	Precipitation:
	Stage 1 — Clear
	Stage 2 — Light clouds
	Stage 3 — Overcast or ground fog
	Stage 4 — Rain, hail or snow
	Stage 5 — Torrential rain, driving hail or blizzard 
	
	Temperature:
	Stage 1 — Unbearable heat
	Stage 2 — Hot
	Stage 3 — Warm
	Stage 4 — Cool
	Stage 5 — Cold
	Stage 6 — Arctic cold 
	
	Wind:
	Stage 1 — Calm
	Stage 2 — Moderate wind
	Stage 3 — Strong wind
	Stage 4 — Gale
	Stage 5 — Storm

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 228</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Create or Destroy Water</name>
				<level>1</level>
				<school>8</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>30 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a drop of water if creating water or a few grains of sand if destroying it)</components>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>You either create or destroy water. 
	Create Water: You create up to 10 gallons of clean water within range in an open container. Alternatively, the water falls as rain in a 30-foot cube within range, extinguishing exposed flames in the area. 
	Destroy Water: You destroy up to 10 gallons of water in an open container within range. Alternatively, you destroy fog in a 30-foot cube within range. 
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you create or destroy 10 additional gallons of water, or the size of the cube increases by 5 feet, for each slot level above 1st.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 229</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Cure Wounds</name>
				<level>1</level>
				<school>5</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>A creature you touch regains a number of hit points equal to 1d8+your spellcasting ability modifier. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs.
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the healing increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 230</text>
				<prepared>1</prepared>
				<roll>1d8+%5</roll>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Darkvision</name>
				<level>2</level>
				<school>8</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<components>V, S, M (either a pinch of dried carrot or an agate)</components>
				<duration>8 hours</duration>
				<text>You touch a willing creature to grant it the ability to see in the dark. For the duration, that creature has darkvision out to a range of 60 feet.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 230</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Daylight</name>
				<level>3</level>
				<school>5</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>60 feet</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>1 hour</duration>
				<text>A 60-foot-radius sphere of light spreads out from a point you choose within range. The sphere is bright light and sheds dim light for an additional 60 feet. 
	If you chose a point on an object you are holding or one that isn't being worn or carried, the light shines from the object with and moves with it. Completely covering the affected object with an opaque object, such as a bowl or a helm, blocks the light.
	If any of this spell's area overlaps with an area of darkness created by a spell of or lower, the spell that created the darkness is dispelled.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 230</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Detect Magic</name>
				<level>1</level>
				<school>3</school>
				<ritual>1</ritual>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
				<text>For the duration, you sense the presence of magic within 30 feet of you. If you sense magic in this way, you can use your action to see a faint aura around any visible creature or object in the area that bears magic, and you learn its school of magic, if any.
	The spell can penetrate most barriers, but is blocked by 1 foot of stone, 1 inch of common metal, a thin sheet of lead, or 3 feet of wood or dirt.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 231</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Detect Poison and Disease</name>
				<level>1</level>
				<school>3</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a yew leaf) </components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
				<text>For the duration, you can sense the presence and location of poisons, poisonous creatures, and diseases within 30 feet of you. You also identify the kind of poison, poisonous creature, or disease in each case. 
	The spell can penetrate most barriers, but is blocked by 1 foot of stone, 1 inch of common metal, a thin sheet of lead, or 3 feet of wood or dirt.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 231</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Dispel Magic</name>
				<level>3</level>
				<school>1</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>120 feet</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>Choose any creature, object, or magical effect within range. Any spell of 3rd level or lower on the target ends. For each spell of or higher on the target, make an ability check using your spellcasting ability. The DC equals 10+the spell's level. On a successful check, the spell ends. 
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, you automatically end the effects of a spell on the target if the spell's level is equal to or less than the level of the spell slot you used.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 234</text>
				<prepared>1</prepared>
				<sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Warlock</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Dominate Beast</name>
				<level>4</level>
				<school>4</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>60 feet</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>You attempt to beguile a beast that you can see within range. It must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be charmed by you for the duration. If you or creatures that are friendly to you are fighting it, it has advantage on the saving throw. 
	While the beast is charmed, you have a telepathic link with it as long as the two of you are on the same plane of existence. You can use this telepathic link to issue commands to the creature while you are conscious (no action required), which it does its best to obey. You can specify a simple and general course of action, such as Attack that creature, Run over there, or Fetch that object. If the creature completes the order and doesn't receive further direction from you, it defends and preserves itself to the best of its ability. 
	You can use your action to take total and precise control of the target. Until the end of your next turn, the creature takes only the actions you choose, and doesn't do anything that you don't allow it to do. During this time, you can also cause the creature to use a reaction, but this requires you to use your own reaction as well. 
	Each time the target takes damage, it makes a new Wisdom saving throw against the spell. If the saving throw succeeds, the spell ends. 
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell with a 5th-level spell slot, the duration is concentration, up to 10 minutes. When you use a 6th-level spell slot, the duration is concentration, up to 1 hour. When you use a spell slot of 7th level or higher, the duration is concentration, up to 8 hours.
	
	Charmed:
	• A charmed creature can't attack the charmer or target the charmer with harmful abilities or magical effects.
	
	• The charmer has advantage on any ability check to interact socially with the creature.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 234</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Warlock (Archfey)</sclass>
				<sclass>Warlock (Great Old One)</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Druidcraft</name>
				<school>8</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>30 feet</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>Whispering to the spirits of nature, you create one of the following effects within range: 
	• You create a tiny, harmless sensory effect that predicts what the weather will be at your location for the next 24 hours. The effect might manifest as a golden orb for clear skies, a cloud for rain, falling snowflakes for snow, and so on. This effect persists for 1 round. 
	• You instantly make a flower blossom, a seed pod open, or a leaf bud bloom. 
	• You create an instantaneous, harmless sensory effect, such as falling leaves, a puff of wind, the sound of a small animal, or the faint odor of skunk. The effect must fit in a 5-foot cube. 
	• You instantly light or snuff out a candle, a torch, or a small campfire. 

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 236</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Earthquake</name>
				<level>8</level>
				<school>5</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>500 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a pinch of dirt, a piece of rock, and a lump of clay)</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>You create a seismic disturbance at a point on the ground that you can see within range. For the duration, an intense tremor rips through the ground in a 100-foot- radius circle centered on that point and shakes creatures and structures in contact with the ground in that area. 
	The ground in the area becomes difficult terrain. Each creature on the ground that is concentrating must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, the creature's concentration is broken. 
	When you cast this spell and at the end of each turn you spend concentrating on it, each creature on the ground in the area must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the creature is knocked prone. 
	This spell can have additional effects depending on the terrain in the area, as determined by the DM. 
	Fissures: Fissures open throughout the spell's area at the start of your next turn after you cast the spell. A total of 1d6 such fissures open in locations chosen by the DM. Each is 1d10 x 10 feet deep, 10 feet wide, and extends from one edge of the spell's area to the opposite side. A creature standing on a spot where a fissure opens must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or fall in. A creature that successfully saves moves with the fissure's edge as it opens. A fissure that opens beneath a structure causes it to automatically collapse (see below). 
	Structures: The tremor deals 50 bludgeoning damage to any structure in contact with the ground in the area when you cast the spell and at the start of each of your turns until the spell ends. If a structure drops to 0 hit points, it collapses and potentially damages nearby creatures. A creature within half the distance of a structure's height must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the creature takes 5d6 bludgeoning damage, is knocked prone, and is buried in the rubble, requiring a DC 20 Strength (Athletics) check as an action to escape. The DM can adjust the DC higher or lower, depending on the nature of the rubble. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage and doesn't fall prone or become buried. 
	
	Prone:
	• A prone creature's only movement option is to crawl, unless it stands up and thereby ends the condition.
	
	• The creature has disadvantage on attack rolls.
	
	• An attack roll against the creature has advantage if the attacker is within 5 feet of the creature. Otherwise, the attack roll has disadvantage.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 236</text>
				<roll>5d6</roll>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Enhance Ability</name>
				<level>2</level>
				<school>8</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<components>V, S, M (fur or a feather from a beast) </components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
				<text>You touch a creature and bestow upon it a magical enhancement. Choose one of the following effects: the target gains the effect until the spell ends. 
	Bear's Endurance: The target has advantage on Constitution checks. It also gains 2d6 temporary hit points, which are lost when the spell ends.
	Bull's Strength: The target has advantage on Strength checks, and his or her carrying capacity doubles.
	Cat's Grace: The target has advantage on Dexterity checks. It also doesn't take damage from falling 20 feet or less if it isn't incapacitated.
	Eagle's Splendor: The target has advantage on Charisma checks.
	Fox's Cunning: The target has advantage on Intelligence checks.
	Owl's Wisdom: The target has advantage on Wisdom checks.
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 2nd.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 237</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Entangle</name>
				<level>1</level>
				<school>2</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>90 feet</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>Grasping weeds and vines sprout from the ground in a 20-foot square starting from a point within range. For the duration, these plants turn the ground in the area into difficult terrain. 
	A creature in the area when you cast the spell must succeed on a Strength saving throw or be restrained by the entangling plants until the spell ends. A creature restrained by the plants can use its action to make a Strength check against your spell save DC. On a success, it frees itself. 
	When the spell ends, the conjured plants wilt away.
	
	Restrained:
	• A restrained creature's speed becomes 0, and it can't benefit from any bonus to its speed.
	
	• Attack rolls against the creature have advantage, and the creature's attack rolls have disadvantage.
	
	• The creature has disadvantage on Dexterity saving throws.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 238</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Faerie Fire</name>
				<level>1</level>
				<school>5</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>60 feet</range>
				<components>V</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>Each object in a 20-foot cube within range is outlined in blue, green, or violet light (your choice). Any creature in the area when the spell is cast is also outlined in light if it fails a Dexterity saving throw. For the duration, objects and affected creatures shed dim light in a 10-foot radius. 
	Any attack roll against an affected creature or object has advantage if the attacker can see it, and the affected creature or object can't benefit from being invisible.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 239</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Warlock (Archfey)</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Feeblemind</name>
				<level>8</level>
				<school>4</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>150 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a handful of clay, crystal, glass, or mineral spheres)</components>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>You blast the mind of a creature that you can see within range, attempting to shatter its intellect and personality. The target takes 4d6 psychic damage and must make an Intelligence saving throw. 
	On a failed save, the creature's Intelligence and Charisma scores become 1. The creature can't cast spells, activate magic items, understand language, or communicate in any intelligible way. The creature can, however, identify its friends, follow them, and even protect them. 
	At the end of every 30 days, the creature can repeat its saving throw against this spell. If it succeeds on its saving throw, the spell ends. 
	The spell can also be ended by greater restoration, heal or wish.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 239</text>
				<roll>4d6</roll>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Warlock</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Feign Death</name>
				<level>3</level>
				<school>7</school>
				<ritual>1</ritual>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a pinch of graveyard dirt)</components>
				<duration>1 hour</duration>
				<text>You touch a willing creature and put it into a cataleptic state that is indistinguishable from death. 
	For the spell's duration, or until you use an action to touch the target and dismiss the spell, the target appears dead to all outward inspection and to spells used to determine the target's status. The target is blinded and incapacitated, and its speed drops to 0. The target has resistance to all damage except psychic damage. If the target is diseased or poisoned when you cast the spell, or becomes diseased or poisoned while under the spell's effect, the disease and poison have no effect until the spell ends.
	
	Blinded:
	• A blinded creature can't see and automatically fails any ability check that requires sight.
	
	• Attack rolls against the creature have advantage, and the creature's attack rolls have disadvantage.
	
	Incapacitated:
	• An incapacitated creature can't take actions or reactions.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 240</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Find Traps</name>
				<level>2</level>
				<school>3</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>120 feet</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>You sense the presence of any trap within range that is within line of sight. A trap, for the purpose of this spell, includes anything that would inflict a sudden or unexpected effect you consider harmful or undesirable, which was specifically intended as such by its creator. Thus, the spell would sense an area affected by the alarm spell, a glyph of warding, or a mechanical pit trap, but it would not reveal a natural weakness in the floor, an unstable ceiling, or a hidden sinkhole. 
	This spell merely reveals that a trap is present. You don't learn the location of each trap, but you do learn the general nature of the danger posed by a trap you sense.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 241</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Find the Path</name>
				<level>6</level>
				<school>3</school>
				<time>1 minute</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a set of divinatory tools — such as bones, ivory sticks, cards, teeth, or carved runes — worth 100 gp and an object from the location you wish to find)</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 day</duration>
				<text>This spell allows you to find the shortest, most direct physical route to a specific fixed location that you are familiar with on the same plane of existence. If you name a destination on another plan of existence, a destination that moves (such as a mobile fortress), or a destination that isn't specific (such as a green dragon's lair), the spell fails. 
	For the duration, as long as you are on the same plane of existence as the destination, you know how far it is and in what direction it lies. While you are traveling there, whenever you are presented with a choice of paths along the way, you automatically determine which path is the shortest and most direct route (but not necessarily the safest route) to the destination.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 240</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Fire Storm</name>
				<level>7</level>
				<school>5</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>150 feet</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>A storm made up of sheets of roaring flame appears in a location you choose within range. The area of the storm consists of up to 10-foot cubes, which you can arrange as you wish. Each cube must have at least one face adjacent to the face of another cube. Each creature in the area must make Dexterity saving throw. It takes 7d10 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. 
	The fire damages objects in the area and ignites flammable objects that aren't being worn or carried. If you choose, plant life in the area is unaffected by this spell.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 242</text>
				<roll>7d10</roll>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Flame Blade</name>
				<level>2</level>
				<school>5</school>
				<time>1 bonus action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<components>V, S, M (leaf of sumac)</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
				<text>You evoke a fiery blade in your free hand. The blade is similar in size and shape to a scimitar, and it lasts for the duration. If you let go of the blade, it disappears, but you can evoke the blade again as a bonus action. 
	You can use your action to make a melee spell attack with the fiery blade. On a hit, the target takes 3d6 fire damage. 
	The flaming blade sheds bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet. 
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for every two slot levels above 2nd.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 242</text>
				<roll>3d6</roll>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Flaming Sphere</name>
				<level>2</level>
				<school>2</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>60 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a bit of tallow, a pinch of brimstone, and a dusting of powdered iron)</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>A 5-foot-diameter sphere of fire appears in an unoccupied space of your choice within range and lasts for the duration. Any creature that ends its turn within 5 feet of the sphere must make a Dexterity saving throw. The creature takes 2d6 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. 
	As a bonus action, you can move the sphere up to 30 feet. If you ram the sphere into a creature, that creature must make the saving throw against the sphere's damage, and the sphere stops moving this turn. 
	When you move the sphere, you can direct it over barriers up to 5 feet tall and jump it across pits up to 10 feet wide. The sphere ignites flammable objects not being worn or carried, and it sheds bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet.
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 2nd.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 242</text>
				<roll>2d6</roll>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Fog Cloud</name>
				<level>1</level>
				<school>2</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>120 feet</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
				<text>You create a 20-foot-radius sphere of fog centered on a point within range. The sphere spreads around corners, and its area is heavily obscured, It lasts for the duration or until a wind of moderate or greater speed (at least 10 miles per hour) disperses it. 
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the radius of the fog increases by 20 feet for each slot level above 1st.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 243</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Foresight</name>
				<level>9</level>
				<school>3</school>
				<time>1 minute</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a hummingbird feather)</components>
				<duration>8 hours</duration>
				<text>You touch a willing creature and bestow a limited ability to see into the immediate future. For the duration, the target can't be surprised and has advantage on attack rolls, ability checks, and saving throws. Additionally, other creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls against the target for the duration. 
	This spell immediately ends if you cast it again before its duration ends.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 244</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Warlock</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Freedom of Movement</name>
				<level>4</level>
				<school>1</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a leather strap, bound around the arm or a similar appendage)</components>
				<duration>1 hour</duration>
				<text>You touch a willing creature. For the duration, the target's movement is unaffected by difficult terrain, and spells and other magical effects can neither reduce the target's speed nor cause the target to be paralyzed or restrained. 
	The target can also spend 5 feet of movement to automatically escape from nonmagical restraints, such as manacles or a creature that has it grappled. Finally, being underwater imposes no penalties on the target's movement or attacks.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 244</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Geas</name>
				<level>5</level>
				<school>4</school>
				<time>1 minute</time>
				<range>60 feet</range>
				<components>V</components>
				<duration>30 days</duration>
				<text>You place a magical command on a creature that you can see within range, forcing it to carry out some service or refrain from some action or course of activity as you decide. If the creature can understand you, it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become charmed by you for the duration. While the creature is charmed by you, it takes 5d10 psychic damage each time it acts in a manner directly counter to your instructions, but no more than once each day. A creature that can't understand you is unaffected by the spell. 
	You can issue any command you choose, short of an activity that would result in certain death. Should you issue a suicidal command, the spell ends. 
	You can end the spell early by using an action to dismiss it. A remove curse, greater restoration, or wish spell also ends it. 
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 7th or 8th level, the duration is 1 year. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of the spell lasts until it is ended by one of the spells mentioned above.
	
	Charmed:
	• A charmed creature can't attack the charmer or target the charmer with harmful abilities or magical effects.
	
	• The charmer has advantage on any ability check to interact socially with the creature.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 244</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Giant Insect</name>
				<level>4</level>
				<school>8</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>30 feet</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
				<text>You transform up to ten centipedes, three spiders, five wasps, or one scorpion within range into giant versions of their natural forms for the duration. A centipede becomes a giant centipede, a spider becomes a giant spider, a wasp becomes a giant wasp, and a scorpion becomes a giant scorpion. 
	Each creature obeys your verbal commands, and in combat, they act on your turn each round. The DM has the statistics for these creatures and resolves their actions and movement.
	A creature remains in its giant size for the duration, until it drops to 0 hit points, or until you use an action to dismiss the effect on it. 
	The DM might allow you to choose different targets. For example, if you transform a bee, its giant version might have the same statistics as a giant wasp.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 245</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Goodberry</name>
				<level>1</level>
				<school>8</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a sprig of mistletoe)</components>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>Up to ten berries appear in your hand and are infused with magic for the duration. A creature can use its action to eat one berry. Eating a berry restores 1 hit point, and the berry provides enough nourishment to sustain a creature for one day. 
	The berries lose their potency if they have not been consumed within 24 hours of the casting of this spell.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 246</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Grasping Vine</name>
				<level>4</level>
				<school>2</school>
				<time>1 bonus action</time>
				<range>30 feet</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>You conjure a vine that sprouts from the ground in an unoccupied space of your choice that you can see within range. When you cast this spell, you can direct the vine to lash out at a creature within 30 feet of it that you can see. That creature must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or be pulled 20 feet directly toward the vine. 
	Until the spell ends, you can direct the vine to lash out at the same creature or another one as a bonus action on each of your turns.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 246</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Greater Restoration</name>
				<level>5</level>
				<school>1</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<components>V, S, M (diamond dust worth 100 gp, which the spell consumes)</components>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>You imbue a creature you touch with positive energy to undo a debilitating effect. You can reduce the target's exhaustion level by one, or end one of the following effects on the target: 
	•  One effect that charmed or petrified the target 
	•  One effect that charmed or petrified the target 
	•  One curse, including the target's attunement to a cursed magic item 
	•  Any reduction to one of the target's ability scores 
	•  One effect reducing the target's hit point maximum

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 246</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Gust of Wind</name>
				<level>2</level>
				<school>5</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self (60-foot line)</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a legume seed)</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>A line of strong wind 60 feet long and 10 feet wide blasts from you in a direction you choose for the spell's duration. Each creature that starts its turn in the line must succeed on a Strength saving throw or be pushed 15 feet away from you in a direction following the line. 
	Any creature in the line must spend 2 feet of movement for every 1 foot it moves when moving closer to you. 
	The gust disperses gas or vapor, and it extinguishes candles, torches, and similar unprotected flames in the area. It causes protected flames, such as those of lanterns, to dance wildly and has a 50 percent chance to extinguish them. 
	As a bonus action on each of your turns before the spell ends, you can change the direction in which the line blasts from you.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 248</text>
				<prepared>1</prepared>
				<sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Hallucinatory Terrain</name>
				<level>4</level>
				<school>6</school>
				<time>10 minutes</time>
				<range>300 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a stone, a twig, and a bit of green plant) </components>
				<duration>24 hours</duration>
				<text>You make natural terrain in a 150-foot cube in range look, sound, and smell like some other sort of natural terrain. Thus, open fields or a road can be made to resemble a swamp, hill, crevasse, or some other difficult or impassable terrain. A pond can be made to seem like a grassy meadow, a precipice like a gentle slope, or a rock-strewn gully like a wide and smooth road. Manufactured structures, equipment, and creatures within the area aren't changed in appearance. 
	The tactile characteristics of the terrain are unchanged, so creatures entering the area are likely to see through the illusion. If the difference isn't obvious by touch, a creature carefully examining the illusion can attempt an Intelligence (Investigation) check against your spell save DC to disbelieve it. A creature who discerns the illusion for what it is, sees it as a vague image superimposed on the terrain.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 249</text>
				<sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Warlock</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Heal</name>
				<level>6</level>
				<school>5</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>60 feet</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>Choose a creature that you can see within range. A surge of positive energy washes through the creature, causing it to regain 70 hit points. The spell also ends blindness, deafness, and any diseases affecting the target. This spell has no effect on constructs or undead. 
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 7th level or higher, the amount of healing increases by 10 for each slot level above 6th.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 250</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Healing Word</name>
				<level>1</level>
				<school>5</school>
				<time>1 bonus action</time>
				<range>60 feet</range>
				<components>V</components>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>A creature of your choice that you can see within range regains hit points equal to 1d4+your spellcasting ability modifier. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs. 
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the healing increases by 1d4 for each slot level above 1st.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 250</text>
				<prepared>1</prepared>
				<roll>1d4+%5</roll>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Heat Metal</name>
				<level>2</level>
				<school>8</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>60 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a piece of iron and a flame) </components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>Choose a manufactured metal object, such as a metal weapon or a suit of heavy or medium metal armor, that you can see within range. You cause the object to glow red-hot. Any creature in physical contact with the object takes 2d8 fire damage when you cast the spell. Until the spell ends, you can use a bonus action on each of your subsequent turns to cause this damage again. 
	If a creature is holding or wearing the object and takes the damage from it, the creature must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or drop the object if it can. If it doesn't drop the object, it has disadvantage on attack rolls and ability checks until the start of your next turn. 
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot above 2nd.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 250</text>
				<roll>2d8</roll>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Heroes' Feast</name>
				<level>6</level>
				<school>2</school>
				<time>10 minutes</time>
				<range>30 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a gem-encrusted bowl worth at least 1,000 gp, which the spell consumes)</components>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>You bring forth a great feast, including magnificent food and drink. The feast takes 1 hour to consume and disappears at the end of that time, and the beneficial effects don't set in until this hour is over. Up to twelve other creatures can partake of the feast. 
	A creature that partakes of the feast gains several benefits. The creature is cured of all diseases and poison, becomes immune to poison and being frightened, and makes all Wisdom saving throws with advantage. Its hit point maximum also increases by 2d10, and it gains the same number of hit points. These benefits last for 24 hours.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 250</text>
				<roll>2d10</roll>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Hold Person</name>
				<level>2</level>
				<school>4</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>60 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a small, straight piece of iron)</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>Choose a humanoid that you can see within range. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be paralyzed for the duration. At the end of each of its turns, the target can make another Wisdom saving throw. On a success, the spell ends on the target. 
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can target on additional humanoid for each slot level above 2nd. The humanoids must be within 30 feet of each other when you target them.
	
	Paralyzed:
	• A paralyzed creature is incapacitated, meaning it can't take actions or reactions, and can't move or speak.
	
	• The creature automatically fails Strength and Dexterity saving throws.
	
	• Attack rolls against the creature have advantage.
	
	• Any attack that hits the creature is a critical hit if the attacker is within 5 feet of the creature.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 251</text>
				<sclass>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</sclass>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Warlock</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Ice Storm</name>
				<level>4</level>
				<school>5</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>300 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a pinch of dust and a few drops of water) </components>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>A hail of rock-hard ice pounds to the ground in a 20-foot-radius, 40-foot-high cylinder centered on a point within range. Each creature in the cylinder must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 2d8 bludgeoning damage and 4d6 cold damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. 
	Hailstones turn the storm's area of effect into difficult terrain until the end of your next turn. 
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the bludgeoning damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 4th.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 252</text>
				<roll>2d8+4d6</roll>
				<sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Insect Plague</name>
				<level>5</level>
				<school>2</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>300 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a few grains of sugar, some kernels of grain, and a smear of fat) </components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
				<text>Swarming, biting locusts fill a 20-foot-radius sphere centered on a point you choose within range. The sphere spreads around corners. The sphere remains for the duration, and its area is lightly obscured. The sphere's area is difficult terrain. 
	When the area appears, each creature in it must make a Constitution saving throw. A creature takes 4d10 piercing damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. A creature must also make this saving throw when it enters the spell's area for the first time on a turn or ends its turn there. 
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d10 for each slot level above 5th.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 254</text>
				<roll>4d10</roll>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Jump</name>
				<level>1</level>
				<school>8</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a grasshopper's hind leg) </components>
				<duration>1 minute</duration>
				<text>You touch a creature. The creature's jump distance is tripled until the spell ends.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 254</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Lesser Restoration</name>
				<level>2</level>
				<school>1</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>You touch a creature and can end either one disease or one condition afflicting it. The condition can be blinded, deafened, paralyzed, or poisoned.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 255</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Locate Animals or Plants</name>
				<level>2</level>
				<school>3</school>
				<ritual>1</ritual>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a bit of fur from a bloodhound) </components>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>Describe or name a specific kind of beast or plant. Concentrating on the voice of nature in your surroundings, you learn the direction and distance to the closest creature or plant of that kind within 5 miles, if any are present.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 256</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Locate Creature</name>
				<level>4</level>
				<school>3</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a bit of fur from a bloodhound) </components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
				<text>Describe or name a creature that is familiar to you. You sense the direction to the creature's location, as long as that creature is within 1,000 feet of you. If the creature is moving, you know the direction of its movement. 
	The spell can locate a specific creature known to you, or the nearest creature of a specific kind (such as a human or a unicorn), so long as you have seen such a creature up close — within 30 feet — at least once. If the creature you described or named is in a different form, such as being under the effects of a polymorph spell, this spell doesn't locate the creature. 
	This spell can't locate a creature if running water at least 10 feet wide blocks a direct path between you and the creature.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 256</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Locate Object</name>
				<level>2</level>
				<school>3</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a forked twig)</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
				<text>Describe or name an object that is familiar to you. You sense the direction to the object's location, as long as that object is within 1,000 feet of you. If the object is in motion, you know the direction of its movement. 
	The spell can locate a specific object known to you, as long as you have seen it up close — within 30 feet — at least once. Alternatively, the spell can locate the nearest object of a particular kind, such as a certain kind of apparel, jewelry, furniture, tool, or weapon. 
	This spell can't locate an object if any thickness of lead, even a thin sheet, blocks a direct path between you and the object.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 256</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Longstrider</name>
				<level>1</level>
				<school>8</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a pinch of dirt)</components>
				<duration>1 hour</duration>
				<text>You touch a creature. The target's speed increases by 10 feet until the spell ends. 
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 1st.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 256</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Mass Cure Wounds</name>
				<level>5</level>
				<school>5</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>60 feet</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>A wave of healing energy washes out from a point of your choice within range. Choose up to six creatures in a 30-foot-radius sphere centered on that point. Each target regains hit points equal to 3d8+your spellcasting ability modifier. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs. 
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the healing increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 5th. 

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 258</text>
				<roll>3d8+%5</roll>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Meld into Stone</name>
				<level>3</level>
				<school>8</school>
				<ritual>1</ritual>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>8 hours</duration>
				<text>You step into a stone object or surface large enough to fully contain your body, melding yourself and all the equipment you carry with the stone for the duration. Using your movement, you step into the stone at a point you can touch. Nothing of your presence remains visible or otherwise detectable by nonmagical senses. 
	While merged with the stone, you can't see what occurs outside it, and any Wisdom (Perception) checks you make to hear sounds outside it are made with disadvantage. You remain aware of the passage of time and can cast spells on yourself while merged in the stone. You can use your movement to leave the stone where you entered it, which ends the spell. You otherwise can't move. 
	Minor physical damage to the stone doesn't harm you, but its partial destruction or a change in its shape (to the extent that you no longer fit within it) expels you and deals 6d6 bludgeoning damage to you. The stone's complete destruction (or transmutation into a different substance) expels you and deals 50 bludgeoning damage to you. If expelled, you fall prone in an unoccupied space closest to where you first entered.
	
	Prone:
	• A prone creature's only movement option is to crawl, unless it stands up and thereby ends the condition.
	
	• The creature has disadvantage on attack rolls.
	
	• An attack roll against the creature has advantage if the attacker is within 5 feet of the creature. Otherwise, the attack roll has disadvantage.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 259</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Mirage Arcane</name>
				<level>7</level>
				<school>6</school>
				<time>10 minutes</time>
				<range>Sight</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>10 days</duration>
				<text>You make terrain in an area up to 1 mile square look, sound, smell, and even feel like some other sort of terrain. The terrain's general shape remains the same, however. Open fields or a road could be made to resemble a swamp, hill, crevasse, or some other difficult or impassable terrain. A pond can be made to seem like a grassy meadow, a precipice like a gentle slope, or a rock-strewn gully like a wide and smooth road. 
	Similarly, you can alter the appearance of structures, or add them where none are present. The spell doesn't disguise, conceal, or add creatures. 
	The illusion includes audible, visual, tactile, and olfactory elements, so it can turn clear ground into difficult terrain (or vice versa) or otherwise impede movement through the area. Any piece of the illusory terrain (such as a rock or stick) that is removed from the spell's area disappears immediately. 
	Creatures with truesight can see through the illusion to the terrain's true form, however, all other elements of the illusion remain, so while the creature is aware of the illusion's presence, the creature can still physically interact with the illusion.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 260</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Moonbeam</name>
				<level>2</level>
				<school>5</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>120 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (several seeds of any moonseed plant and a piece of opalescent feldspar) </components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>A silvery beam of pale light shines down in a 5-foot-radius, 40-foot-high cylinder centered on a point within range. Until the spell ends, dim light fills the cylinder. 
	When a creature enters the spell's area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, it is engulfed in ghostly flames that cause searing pain, and it must make a Constitution saving throw. It takes 2d10 radiant damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. 
	A shapechanger makes its saving throw with disadvantage. If it fails, it also instantly reverts to its original form and can't assume a different form until it leaves the spell's light. 
	On each of your turns after you cast this spell, you can use an action to move the beam 60 feet in any direction. 
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d10 for each slot level above 2nd.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 261</text>
				<prepared>1</prepared>
				<roll>2d10</roll>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Move Earth</name>
				<level>6</level>
				<school>8</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>120 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (an iron blade and a small bag containing a mixture of soils — clay, loam, and sand) </components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 2 hours</duration>
				<text>Choose an area of terrain no larger than 40 feet on a side within range. You can reshape dirt, sand, or clay in the area in any manner you choose for the duration. You can raise or lower the area's elevation, create or fill in a trench, erect or flatten a wall, or form a pillar. The extent of any such changes can't exceed half the area's largest dimension. So, if you affect a 40-foot square, you can create a pillar up to 20 feet high, raise or lower the square's elevation by up to 20 feet, dig a trench up to 20 feet deep, and so on. It takes 10 minutes for these changes to complete. 
	At the end of every 10 minutes you spend concentrating on the spell, you can choose a new area of terrain to affect. 
	Because the terrain's transformation occurs slowly, creatures in the area can't usually be trapped or injured by the ground's movement. 
	This spell can't manipulate natural stone or stone construction. Rocks and structures shift to accommodate the new terrain. If the way you shape the terrain would make a structure unstable, it might collapse. 
	Similarly, this spell doesn't directly affect plant growth. The moved earth carries any plants along with it.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 263</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Pass Without Trace</name>
				<level>2</level>
				<school>1</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<components>V, S, M (ashes from a burned leaf of mistletoe and a sprig of spruce) </components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
				<text>A veil of shadows and silence radiates from you, masking you and your companions from detection. For the duration, each creature you choose within 30 feet of you (including you) has a +10 bonus to Dexterity (Stealth) checks and can't be tracked except by magical means. A creature that receives this bonus leaves behind no tracks or other traces of its passage.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 264</text>
				<prepared>1</prepared>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Planar Binding</name>
				<level>5</level>
				<school>1</school>
				<time>1 hour</time>
				<range>60 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a jewel worth at least 1,000 gp, which the spell consumes) </components>
				<duration>24 hours</duration>
				<text>With this spell, you attempt to bind a celestial, an elemental, a fey, or a fiend to your service. The creature must be within range for the entire casting of the spell. (Typically, the creature is first summoned into the center of an inverted magic circle in order to keep it trapped while this spell is cast.) At the completion of the casting, the target must make a Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, it is bound to serve you for the duration. If the creature w as summoned or created by another spell, that spell's duration is extended to match the duration of this spell. 
	A bound creature must follow your instructions to the best of its ability. You might command the creature to accompany you on an adventure, to guard a location, or to deliver a message. The creature obeys the letter of your instructions, but if the creature is hostile to you, it strives to twist your words to achieve its own objectives. If the creature carries out your instructions completely before the spell ends, it travels to you to report this fact if you are on the same plane of existence. If you are on a different plane of existence, it returns to the place where you bound it and remains there until the spell ends. 
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of a higher level, the duration increases to 10 days with a 6th-level slot, to 30 days with a 7th-level slot, to 180 days with an 8th-level slot, and to a year and a day with a 9th-level spell slot. 

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 265</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Plane Shift</name>
				<level>7</level>
				<school>2</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a forked, metal rod worth at least 250 gp, attuned to a particular plane of existence)</components>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>You and up to eight willing creatures who link hands in a circle are transported to a different plane of existence. You can specify a target destination in general terms, such as the City of Brass on the Elemental Plane of Fire or the palace of Dispater on the second level of the Nine Hells, and you appear in or near that destination. If you are trying to reach the City of Brass, for example, you might arrive in its Street of Steel, before its Gate of Ashes, or looking at the city from across the Sea of Fire, at the DM's discretion. 
	Alternatively, if you know the sigil sequence of a teleportation circle on another plane of existence, this spell can take you to that circle. If the teleportation circle is too small to hold all the creatures you transported, they appear in the closest unoccupied spaces next to the circle. 
	You can use this spell to banish an unwilling creature to another plane. Choose a creature within your reach and make a melee spell attack against it. On a hit, the creature must make a Charisma saving throw. If the creature fails the save, it is transported to a random location on the plane of existence you specify. A creature so transported must find its own way back to your current plane of existence.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 266</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Warlock</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Plant Growth</name>
				<level>3</level>
				<school>8</school>
				<time>1 action or 8 hours</time>
				<range>150 feet</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>This spell channels vitality into plants within a specific area. There are two possible uses for the spell, granting either immediate or long-term benefits. 
	If you cast this spell using 1 action, choose a point within range. All normal plants in a 100-foot radius centered on that point become thick and overgrown. A creature moving through the area must spend 4 feet of movement for every 1 foot it moves. 
	You can exclude one or more areas of any size within the spell's area from being affected. 
	If you cast this spell over 8 hours, you enrich the land. All plants in a half-mile radius centered on a point within range become enriched for 1 year. The plants yield twice the normal amount of food when harvested.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 266</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
				<sclass>Warlock (Archfey)</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Polymorph</name>
				<level>4</level>
				<school>8</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>60 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a caterpillar cocoon)</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
				<text>This spell transforms a creature that you can see within range into a new form. An unwilling creature must make a Wisdom saving throw to avoid the effect. A shapechanger automatically succeeds on this saving throw. 
	The transformation lasts for the duration, or until the target drops to 0 hit points or dies. The new form can be any beast whose challenge rating is equal to or less than the target's (or the target's level, if it doesn't have a challenge rating). The target's game statistics, including mental ability scores, are replaced by the statistics of the chosen beast. It retains its alignment and personality. 
	The target assumes the hit points of its new form. When it reverts to its normal form, the creature returns to the number of hit points it had before it transformed. If it reverts as a result of dropping to 0 hit points, any excess damage carries over to its normal form. As long as the excess damage doesn't reduce the creature's normal form to 0 hit points, it isn't knocked unconscious. 
	The creature is limited in the actions it can perform by the nature of its new form, and it can't speak, cast spells, or take any other action that requires hands or speech. 
	The target's gear melds into the new form. The creature can't activate, use, wield, or otherwise benefit from any of its equipment.
	This spell can’t affect a target that has 0 hit points.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 266</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Produce Flame</name>
				<school>2</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>10 minutes</duration>
				<text>A flickering flame appears in your hand. The flame remains there for the duration and harms neither you nor your equipment. The flame sheds bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet. The spell ends if you dismiss it as an action or if you cast it again. 
	You can also attack with the flame, although doing so ends the spell. When you cast this spell, or as an action on a later turn, you can hurl the flame at a creature within 30 feet of you. Make a ranged spell attack. On a hit, the target takes 1d8 fire damage. 
	This spell's damage increases by 1d8 when you reach 5th level (2d8), 11th level (3d8), and 17th level (4d8).

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 269</text>
				<roll>1d8</roll>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Protection from Energy</name>
				<level>3</level>
				<school>1</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
				<text>For the duration, the willing creature you touch has resistance to one damage type of your choice: acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 270</text>
				<sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Protection from Poison</name>
				<level>2</level>
				<school>1</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>1 hour</duration>
				<text>You touch a creature. If it is poisoned, you neutralize the poison. If more than one poison afflicts the target, you neutralize one poison that you know is present, or you neutralize one at random. 
	For the duration, the target has advantage on saving throws against being poisoned, and it has resistance to poison damage.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 270</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Purify Food and Drink</name>
				<level>1</level>
				<school>8</school>
				<ritual>1</ritual>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>10 feet</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>All nonmagical food and drink within a 5-foot-radius sphere centered on a point of your choice within range is purified and rendered free of poison and disease.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 270</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Regenerate</name>
				<level>7</level>
				<school>8</school>
				<time>1 minute</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a prayer wheel and holy water) </components>
				<duration>1 hour</duration>
				<text>You touch a creature and stimulate its natural healing ability. The target regains 4d8+15 hit points. For the duration of the spell, the target regains 1 hit point at the start of each of its turns (10 hit points each minute). 
	The target's severed body members (fingers, legs, tails, and so on), if any, are restored after 2 minutes. If you have the severed part and hold it to the stump, the spell instantaneously causes the limb to knit to the stump. 

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 271</text>
				<roll>4d8+15</roll>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Reincarnate</name>
				<level>5</level>
				<school>8</school>
				<time>1 hour</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<components>V, S, M (rare oils and unguents worth at least 1,000 gp, which the spell consumes) </components>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>You touch a dead humanoid or a piece of a dead humanoid. Provided that the creature has been dead no longer than 10 days, the spell forms a new adult body for it and then calls the soul to enter that body. If the target's soul isn't free or willing to do so, the spell fails. 
	The magic fashions a new body for the creature to inhabit, which likely causes the creature's race to change. The DM rolls a d100 and consults the following table to determine what form the creature takes when restored to life, or the DM chooses a form. 
	01-04 — Dragonborn
	05-13 — Dwarf, hill
	14-21 — Dwarf, mountain
	22-25 — Elf, dark
	26-34 — Elf, high
	35-42 — Elf, wood
	43-46 — Gnome, forest
	47-52 — Gnome, rock
	53-56 — Half-elf
	57-60 — Half-orc
	61-68 — Halfling, lightfoot
	69-76 — Halfling, stout
	77-96 — Human
	97-00 — Tiefling 
	The reincarnated creature recalls its former life and experiences. It retains the capabilities it had in its original form, except it exchanges its original race for the new one and changes its racial traits accordingly. 

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 271</text>
				<roll>1d100</roll>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Reverse Gravity</name>
				<level>7</level>
				<school>8</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>100 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a lodestone and iron filings) </components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>This spell reverses gravity in a 50-foot-radius, 100-foot high cylinder centered on a point within range. All creatures and objects that aren't somehow anchored to the ground in the area fall upward and reach the top of the area when you cast this spell. A creature can make a Dexterity saving throw to grab onto a fixed object it can reach, thus avoiding the fall. 
	If some solid object (such as a ceiling) is encountered in this fall, falling objects and creatures strike it just as they would during a normal downward fall. If an object or creature reaches the top of the area without striking anything, it remains there, oscillating slightly, for the duration. 
	At the end of the duration, affected objects and creatures fall back down.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 272</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Scrying</name>
				<level>5</level>
				<school>3</school>
				<time>10 minutes</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a focus worth at least 1,000 gp, such as a crystal ball, a silver mirror, or a font filled with holy water) </components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
				<text>You can see and hear a particular creature you choose that is on the same plane of existence as you. The target must make a Wisdom saving throw, which is modified by how well you know the target and the sort of physical connection you have to it. If a target knows you're casting this spell, it can fail the saving throw voluntarily if it wants to be observed.
	
	Knowledge — Save Modifier: 
	Secondhand (you have heard of the target) — +5 
	Firsthand (you have met the target) — +0
	Familiar (you know the target well) — -5
	
	Connection — Save Modifier: 
	Likeness or picture — -2
	Possession or garment — -4
	Body part, lock of hair, bit of nail, or the like — -10 
	
	On a successful save, the target isn't affected, and you can't use this spell against it again for 24 hours. 
	On a failed save, the spell creates an invisible sensor within 10 feet of the target. You can see and hear through the sensor as if you were there. The sensor moves with the target, remaining within 10 feet of it for the duration. A creature that can see invisible objects sees the sensor as a luminous orb about the size of your fist. 
	Instead of targeting a creature, you can choose a location you have seen before as the target of this spell. When you do, the sensor appears at that location and doesn't move.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 273</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Warlock</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Shapechange</name>
				<level>9</level>
				<school>8</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a jade circlet worth at least 1,500 gp, which you must place on your head before you cast the spell) </components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
				<text>You assume the form of a different creature for the duration. The new form can be any creature with a challenge rating equal to your level or lower. The creature can't be a construct or an undead, and you must have seen the sort of creature at least once. You transform into an average example of that creature, one without any class levels or the Spellcasting trait. 
	Your game statistics are replaced by the statistics of the chosen creature, though you retain your alignment and Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma scores You also retain all of your skill and saving throw proficiencies, in addition to gaining those of the creature, If the creature has the same proficiency as you, and the bonus listed in its statistics is higher than yours, use the creature's bonus in place of yours. You can't use any legendary actions or lair actions of the new form. 
	You assume the hit points and Hit Dice of the new form. When you revert to your normal, you return to the number of hit points you had before you transformed. If you revert as a result of dropping to 0 hit points, any excess damage carries over to your normal form. As long as the excess damage doesn't reduce your normal form to 0 hit points, you aren't knocked unconscious. 
	You retain the benefit of any features from your class, race, or other source and can use them, provided that your new form is physically capable of doing so. You can't use any special senses you have (for example, darkvision) unless your new form also has that sense. You can only speak if the creature can normally speak. 
	When you transform, you choose whether your equipment falls to the ground, merges into the new form, or is worn by it. Worn equipment functions as normal. The DM determines whether it is practical for the new form to wear a piece of equipment, based on the creature's shape and size. Your equipment doesn't change shape or size to match the new form, and any equipment that the new form can't wear must either fall to the ground or merge into your new form. Equipment that merges has no effect in that state. 
	During this spell's duration, you can use your action to assume a different form following the same restrictions and rules for the original form, with one exception: if your new form has more hit pints than your current one, your hit points remain at their current value.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 274</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Sleet Storm</name>
				<level>3</level>
				<school>2</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>150 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a pinch of dust and a few drops of water) </components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>Until the spell ends, freezing rain and sleet fall in a 20-foot-tall cylinder with a 40-foot radius centered on a point you choose within range. The area is heavily obscured, and exposed flames in the area are doused. 
	The ground in the area is covered with slick ice, making it difficult terrain. When a creature enters the spell's area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, it must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, it falls prone. 
	If a creature is concentrating in the spell's area, the creature must make a successful Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC or lose concentration.
	
	Prone:
	• A prone creature's only movement option is to crawl, unless it stands up and thereby ends the condition.
	
	• The creature has disadvantage on attack rolls.
	
	• An attack roll against the creature has advantage if the attacker is within 5 feet of the creature. Otherwise, the attack roll has disadvantage.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 276</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Speak with Animals</name>
				<level>1</level>
				<school>3</school>
				<ritual>1</ritual>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>10 minutes</duration>
				<text>You gain the ability to comprehend and verbally communicate with beasts for the duration. The knowledge and awareness of many beasts is limited by their intelligence, but at minimum, beasts can give you information about nearby locations and monsters, including whatever they can perceive or have perceived within the past day. You might be able to persuade a beast to perform a small favor for you, at the DM's discretion.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 277</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Speak with Plants</name>
				<level>3</level>
				<school>8</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self (30-foot radius)</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>10 minutes</duration>
				<text>You imbue plants within 30 feet of you with limited sentience and animation, giving them the ability to communicate with you and follow your simple commands. You can question plants about events in the spell's area within the past day, gaining information about creatures that have passed, weather, and other circumstances. 
	You can also turn difficult terrain caused by plant growth (such as thickets and undergrowth) into ordinary terrain that lasts for the duration. Or you can turn ordinary terrain where plants are present into difficult terrain that lasts for the duration, causing vines and branches to hinder pursuers, for example. 
	Plants might be able to perform other tasks on your behalf, at the DM's discretion. The spell doesn't enable plants to uproot themselves and move about, but they can freely move branches, tendrils, and stalks. 
	If a plant creature is in the area, you can communicate with it as if you shard a common language, but you gain no magical ability to influence it. 
	This spell can cause the plants created by the entangle spell to release a restrained creature.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 277</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Spike Growth</name>
				<level>2</level>
				<school>8</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>150 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (seven sharp thorns or seven small twigs, each sharpened to a point)</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
				<text>The ground in a 20-foot radius centered on a point within range twists and sprouts hard spikes and thorns. The area becomes difficult terrain for the duration. When a creature moves into or within the area, it takes 2d4 piercing damage for every 5 feet it travels. 
	The transformation of the ground is camouflaged to look natural. Any creature that can't see the area at the time the spell is case must make a Wisdom (Perception) check against your spell save DC to recognize the terrain as hazardous before entering it.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 277</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Stone Shape</name>
				<level>4</level>
				<school>8</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<components>V, S, M (soft clay, which must be worked into roughly the desired shape of the stone object) </components>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>You touch a stone object of Medium size or smaller or a section of stone no more than 5 feet in any dimension and form it into any shape that suits your purpose. So, for example, you could shape a large rock into a weapon, idol, or coffer, or make a small passage through a wall, as long as the wall is less than 5 feet thick. You could also shape a stone door or its frame to seal the door shut. The object you create can have up to two hinges and a latch, but finer mechanical detail isn't possible.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 278</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Stoneskin</name>
				<level>4</level>
				<school>1</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<components>V, S, M (diamond dust worth 100 gp, which the spell consumes) </components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
				<text>This spell turns the flesh of a willing creature you touch as hard as stone. Until the spell ends, the target has resistance to nonmagical bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 278</text>
				<sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Storm of Vengeance</name>
				<level>9</level>
				<school>2</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Sight</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>A churning storm cloud forms, centered on a point you can see and spreading to a radius of 360 feet. Lightning flashes in the area, thunder booms, and strong winds roar. Each creature under the cloud (no more than 5,000 feet beneath the cloud) when it appears must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 2d6 thunder damage and becomes deafened for 5 minutes. 
	Each round you maintain concentration on this spell, the storm produces additional effects on your turn. 
	Round 2: Acidic rain falls from the cloud. Each creature and object under the cloud takes 1d6 acid damage. 
	Round 3: You call six bolts of lightning from the cloud to strike six creatures or objects of your choice beneath the cloud. A given creature or object can't be struck by more than one bolt. A struck creature must make a Dexterity saving throw. The creature takes 10d6 lightning damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. 
	Round 4: Hailstones rain down from the cloud. Each creature under the cloud takes 2d6 bludgeoning damage. 
	Round 5-10: Gusts and freezing rain assail the area under the cloud. the area becomes difficult terrain and is heavily obscured. Each creature there takes 1d6 cold damage. Ranged weapon attacks in the area are impossible. The wind and rain count as a severe distraction for the purposes of maintaining concentration on spells. Finally, gusts of strong wind (ranging from 20 to 50 miles per hour) automatically disperse fog, mists, and similar phenomena in the area whether mundane or magical.
	
	Deafened:
	• A deafened creature can't hear and automatically fails any ability check that requires hearing. 

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 279</text>
				<roll>1d6</roll>
				<roll>10d6</roll>
				<roll>2d6</roll>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Sunbeam</name>
				<level>6</level>
				<school>5</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self (60-foot line)</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a magnifying glass) </components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>A beam of brilliant light flashes out from your hand in a 5-foot-wide, 60-foot-line. Each creature in the line must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 6d8 radiant damage and is blinded until your next turn. On a successful save, it takes half as much damage and isn't blinded by this spell. Undead and oozes have disadvantage on this saving throw. 
	You can create a new line of radiance as your action on any turn until the spell ends. 
	For the duration, a mote of brilliant radiance shines in your hand. It sheds bright light in a 30-foot radius and dim light for an additional 30 feet. The light is sunlight.
	
	Blinded:
	• A blinded creature can't see and automatically fails any ability check that requires sight.
	
	• Attack rolls against the creature have advantage, and the creature's attack rolls have disadvantage.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 279</text>
				<roll>6d8</roll>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Sunburst</name>
				<level>8</level>
				<school>5</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>150 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (fire and a piece of sunstone)</components>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>Brilliant sunlight flashes in a 60-foot radius centered on a point you choose within range. Each creature in that light must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 12d6 radiant damage and is blinded for 1 minute. On a successful save, it takes half as much damage and isn't blinded by this spell. Undead and oozes have disadvantage on this saving throw. 
	A creature blinded by this spell makes another Constitution saving throw at the end of each of its turns. On a successful save, it is no longer blinded. 
	This spell dispels any darkness in its area that was created by a spell.
	
	Blinded:
	• A blinded creature can't see and automatically fails any ability check that requires sight.
	
	• Attack rolls against the creature have advantage, and the creature's attack rolls have disadvantage.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 279</text>
				<roll>12d6</roll>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Thorn Whip</name>
				<school>8</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>30 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M </components>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>You create a long, vine-like whip covered in thorns that lashes out at your command toward a creature in range. Make a melee spell attack against the target. If the attack hits, the creature takes 1d6 piercing damage, and if the creature is Large or smaller, you pull the creature up to 10 feet closer to you.
	This spell's damage increases by 1d6 when you reach 5th level (2d6), 11th level (3d6), and 17th level (4d6).

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 282</text>
				<roll>1d6</roll>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Thunderwave</name>
				<level>1</level>
				<school>5</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self (15-foot cube)</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>A wave of thunderous force sweeps out from you. Each creature in a 15-foot cube originating from you must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 2d8 thunder damage and is pushed 10 feet away from you. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage and isn't pushed. 
	In addition, unsecured objects that are completely within the area of effect are automatically pushed 10 feet away from you by the spell's effect, and the spell emits a thunderous boom audible out to 300 feet. 
	
	At Higher Levels: 
	When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 282</text>
				<prepared>1</prepared>
				<roll>2d8</roll>
				<sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Transport via Plants</name>
				<level>6</level>
				<school>2</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>10 feet</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>1 round</duration>
				<text>This spell creates a magical link between a Large or larger inanimate plant within range and another plant, at any distance, on the same plane of existence. You must have seen or touched the destination plant at least once before. For the duration, any creature can step into the target plant and exit from the destination plant by using 5 feet of movement. 

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 283</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Tree Stride</name>
				<level>5</level>
				<school>2</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>You gain the ability to enter a tree and move from inside it to inside another tree of the same kind within 500 feet. Both trees must be living and at least the same size as you. You must use 5 feet of movement to enter a tree. You instantly know the location of all other trees of the same kind within 500 feet and, as part of the move used to enter the tree, can either pass into one of those trees or step out of the tree you're in. You appear in a spot of your choice within 5 feet of the destination tree, using another 5 feet of movement. If you have no movement left, you appear within 5 feet of the tree you entered. 
	You can use this transportation ability once per round for the duration. You must end each turn outside a tree. 

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 283</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>True Resurrection</name>
				<level>9</level>
				<school>7</school>
				<time>1 hour</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a sprinkle of holy water and diamonds worth at least 25,000 gp, which the spell consumes)</components>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>You touch a creature that has been dead for no longer than 200 years and that died for any reason except old age. If the creature's soul is free and willing, the creature is restored to life with all its hit points. 
	This spell closes all wounds, neutralizes any poison, cures all diseases, and lifts any curses affecting the creature when it died. The spell replaces damaged or missing organs or limbs. 
	The spell can even provide a new body if the original no longer exists, in which case you must speak the creature's name. The creature then appears in an unoccupied space you choose within 10 feet of you.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 284</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Tsunami</name>
				<level>8</level>
				<school>2</school>
				<time>1 minute</time>
				<range>Sight</range>
				<components>V, S</components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 6 rounds</duration>
				<text>A wall of water springs into existence at a point you choose within range. You can make the wall up to 300 feet long, 300 feet high, and 50 feet thick. The wall lasts for the duration. 
	When the wall appears, each creature within its area must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 6d10 bludgeoning damage, or half as much damage on a successful save. 
	At the start of each of your turns after the wall appears, the wall, along with any creatures in it, moves 50 feet away from you. Any Huge or smaller creature inside the wall or whose space the wall enters when it moves must succeed on a Strength saving throw or take 5d10 bludgeoning damage. A creature can take this damage only once per round. At the end of the turn, the wall's height is reduced by 50 feet, and the damage creatures take from the spell on subsequent rounds is reduced by 1d10. When the wall reaches 0 feet in height, the spell ends. 
	A creature caught in the wall can move by swimming. Because of the force of the wave, though, the creature must make a successful Strength (Athletics) check against your spell save DC in order to move at all. If it fails the check, it can't move. A creature that moves out of the area falls to the ground.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 284</text>
				<roll>6d10</roll>
				<roll>5d10</roll>
				<roll>4d10</roll>
				<roll>3d10</roll>
				<roll>2d10</roll>
				<roll>1d10</roll>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Wall of Fire</name>
				<level>4</level>
				<school>5</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>120 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a small piece of phosphorus) </components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>You create a wall of fire on a solid surface within range. You can make the wall up to 60 feet long, 20 feet high, and 1 foot think, or a ringed wall up to 20 feet in diameter, 20 feet high, and 1 foot think. The wall is opaque and lasts for the duration. 
	When the wall appears, each creature within its area must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 5d8 fire damage, or half as much damage on a successful save. 
	One side of the wall, selected by you when you cast this spell, deals 5d8 fire damage to each creature that ends its turn within 10 feet of that side or inside the wall. A creature takes the same damage when it enters the wall for the first time on a turn or ends its turn there. The other side of the wall deals no damage. 
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 4th.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 285</text>
				<roll>5d8</roll>
				<sclass>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Warlock (Fiend)</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Wall of Stone</name>
				<level>5</level>
				<school>5</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>120 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a small block of granite) </components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
				<text>A nonmagical wall of solid stone springs into existence at a point you choose within range. The wall is 6 inches thick and is composed of ten 10-foot-by-10-foot panels. Each panel must be contiguous with at least on other panel. Alternatively, you can create 10-foot-by-20-foot panels that are only 3 inches thick. 
	If the wall cuts through a creature's space when it appears, the creature is pushed to one side of the wall (your choice). If a creature would be surrounded on all sides by the wall (or the wall and another solid surface), that creature can make a Dexterity saving throw. On a success, it can use its reaction to move up to its speed so that it is no longer enclosed by the wall. 
	The wall can have any shape you desire, though it can't occupy the same space as a creature or object. the wall doesn't need to be vertical or resting on any firm foundation. It must, however, merge with and be solidly supported by existing stone. Thus you can use this spell to bridge a chasm or create a ramp. 
	If you create a span greater than 20 feet in length, you must halve the size of each panel to create supports. You can crudely shape the wall to create crenellations, battlements, and so on. 
	The wall is an object made of stone that can be damaged and thus breached. Each panel has AC 15 and 30 hit points per inch of thickness. Reducing a panel to 0 hit points destroys it and might cause connected panels to collapse at the DM's discretion. 
	If you maintain your concentration on this spell for its whole duration, the wall becomes permanent and can't be dispelled. Otherwise, the wall disappears when the spell ends.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 287</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Wall of Thorns</name>
				<level>6</level>
				<school>2</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>120 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a handful of thorns) </components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
				<text>You create a wall of tough, pliable, tangled brush bristling with needle-sharp thorns. The wall appears within range on a solid surface and lasts for the duration. You choose to make the wall up to 60 feet long, 10 feet high, and 5 feet thick or a circle that has a 20-foot diameter and is up to 20 feet high and 5 feet thick. The wall blocks line of sight.
	When the wall appears, each creature within its area must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 7d8 piercing damage, or half as much damage on a successful save. 
	A creature can move through the wall, albeit slowly and painfully. For every 1 foot a creature moves through the wall, it must spend 4 feet of movement. Furthermore, the first time a creature enters the wall on a turn or ends its turn there, the creature must make a Dexterity saving throw. It takes 7d8 slashing damage on a failed save, or half as much on a successful save. 
	
	At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 7th level or higher, both types of damage increase by 1d8 for each slot level above 6th.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 287</text>
				<roll>7d8</roll>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Water Breathing</name>
				<level>3</level>
				<school>8</school>
				<ritual>1</ritual>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>30 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a short reed or piece of straw) </components>
				<duration>24 hours</duration>
				<text>This spell grants up to ten willing creatures you can see within range the ability to breathe underwater until the spell ends. Affected creatures also retain their normal mode of respiration.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 287</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Water Walk</name>
				<level>3</level>
				<school>8</school>
				<ritual>1</ritual>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>30 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a piece of cork) </components>
				<duration>1 hour</duration>
				<text>This spell grants the ability to move across any liquid surface — such as water, acid, mud, snow, quicksand, or lava — as if it were harmless solid ground (creatures crossing molten lava can still take damage from the heat). Up to ten willing creatures you can see within range gain this ability for the duration. 
	If your target a creature submerged in a liquid, the spell carries the target to the surface of the liquid at a rate of 60 feet per round.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 287</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Wind Walk</name>
				<level>6</level>
				<school>8</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>30 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (fire and holy water) </components>
				<duration>8 hours</duration>
				<text>You and up to ten willing creatures you can see within range assume a gaseous form for the duration, appearing as wisps of cloud. While in this cloud form, a creature has a flying speed of 300 feet and has resistance to damage from nonmagical weapons. The only actions a creature can take in this form are the Dash action or to revert to its normal form. Reverting takes 1 minute, during which time a creature is incapacitated and can't move. Until the spell ends, a creature can revert to cloud form, which also requires the 1-minute transformation. 
	If a creature is in cloud form and flying when the effect ends, the creature descends 60 feet per round for 1 minute until it lands, which it does safely. If it can't land after 1 minute, the creature falls the remaining distance.
	
	Incapacitated:
	• An incapacitated creature can't take actions or reactions.

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 288</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Wind Wall</name>
				<level>3</level>
				<school>5</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>120 feet</range>
				<components>V, S, M (a tiny fan and a feather of exotic origin) </components>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>A wall of strong wind rises from the ground at a point you choose within range. You can make the wall up to 50 feet long, 15 feet high, and 1 foot thick. You can shape the wall in any way you choose so long as it makes one continuous path along the ground. The wall lasts for the duration. 
	When the wall appears, each creature within its area must make a Strength saving throw. A creature takes 3d8 bludgeoning damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. 
	The strong wind keeps fog, smoke, and other gases at bay. Small or smaller flying creatures or objects can't pass through the wall. Loose, lightweight materials brought into the wall fly upward. Arrows, bolts, and other ordinary projectiles launched at targets behind the wall are deflected upward and automatically miss. (Boulders hurled by giants or siege engines, and similar projectiles, are unaffected.) Creatures in gaseous form can't pass through it. 

	Source: Player's Handbook p. 288</text>
				<roll>3d8</roll>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<feat>
				<name>Starting Proficiencies</name>
				<text>Armor: light armor, medium armor, shields (druids will not wear armor or use shields made of metal)
	
	Weapons: clubs, daggers, darts, javelins, maces, quarterstaffs, scimitars, sickles, slings, spears
	
	Tools: herbalism kit</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
				<proficiency>110</proficiency>
				<proficiency>101</proficiency>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Druidic</name>
				<text>You know Druidic, the secret language of druids. You can speak the language and use it to leave hidden messages. You and others who know this language automatically spot such a message. Others spot the message's presence with a successful DC 15 Wisdom (Perception) check but can't decipher it without magic.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Spellcasting</name>
				<text>Cantrips:
	At 1st level, you know two cantrips of your choice from the druid spell list. You learn an additional druid cantrip of your choice at 4th level and another at 10th level. 
	
	Preparing and Casting Spells:
	The Druid table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these druid spells, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.
	You prepare the list of druid spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the druid spell list. When you do so, choose a number of druid spells equal to your Wisdom modifier + your druid level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.
	You can also change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of druid spells requires time spent in prayer and meditation: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list. 
	
	Spellcasting Ability:
	Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your druid spells, since your magic draws upon your devotion and attunement to nature. You use your Wisdom whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a druid spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.
	Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier
	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier 
	
	Ritual Casting:
	You can cast a druid spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell prepared. 
	
	Spellcasting Focus:
	You can use a druidic focus (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your druid spells.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<optional>1</optional>
				<name>Combat Wild Shape (Circle of the Moon)</name>
				<text>When you choose this circle at 2nd level, you gain the ability to use Wild Shape on your turn as a bonus action, rather than as an action.
	Additionally, while you are transformed by Wild Shape, you can use a bonus action to expend one spell slot to regain 1d8 hit points per level of the spell slot expended.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<optional>1</optional>
				<name>Circle Forms (Circle of the Moon)</name>
				<text>The rites of your circle grant you the ability to transform into more dangerous animal forms. Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Wild Shape to transform into a beast with a challenge rating as high as 1 (you ignore the Max. CR column of the Beast Shapes table, but must abide by the other limitations there).
	Starting at 6th level, you can transform into a beast with a challenge rating as high as your druid level divided by 3, rounded down.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Wild Shape</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your action to magically assume the shape of a beast that you have seen before. You can use this feature twice. You regain expended uses when you finish a short or long rest.
	Your druid level determines the beasts you can transform into, as shown in the Beast Shapes table (Player's Handbook, p. 66).
	At 2nd level, you can transform into any beast that has a challenge rating of 1/4 or lower that doesn't have a flying or swimming speed.  At 4th level, you can transform into any beast that has a challenge rating of 1/2 or lower that doesn't have a flying speed.  At 8th level, you can transform into any beast that has a challenge rating of 1 or lower.
	You can stay in a beast shape for a number of hours equal to half your druid level (rounded down). You then revert to your normal form unless you expend another use of this feature. You can revert to your normal form earlier by using a bonus action on your turn. You automatically revert if you fall unconscious, drop to 0 hit points, or die.
	While you are transformed, the following rules apply.
	
	• Your game statistics are replaced by the statistics of the beast, but you retain your alignment, personality, and Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma scores. You also retain all of your skill and saving throw proficiencies, in addition to gaining those of the creature. If the creature has the same proficiency as you and the bonus in its stat block is higher than yours, use the creature's bonus instead of yours. If the creature has any legendary or lair actions, you can't use them.
	
	• When you transform, you assume the beast's hit points and Hit Dice. When you revert to your normal form, you return to the number of hit points you had before you transformed. However, if you revert as a result of dropping to 0 hit points, any excess damage carries over to your normal form. For example, if you take 10 damage in animal form and have only 1 hit point left, you revert and take 9 damage. As long as the excess damage doesn't reduce your normal form to 0 hit points, you aren't knocked unconscious.
	
	• You can't cast spells, and your ability to speak or take any action that requires hands is limited to the capabilities of your beast form. Transforming doesn't break your concentration on a spell you've already cast, however, or prevent you from taking actions that are part of a spell, such as call lightning, that you've already cast.
	
	• You retain the benefit of any features from your class, race, or other source and can use them if the new form is physically capable of doing so. However, you can't use any of your special senses, such as darkvision, unless your new form also has that sense.
	
	• You choose whether your equipment falls to the ground in your space, merges into your new form, or is worn by it. Worn equipment functions as normal, but the DM decides whether it is practical for the new form to wear a piece of equipment, based on the creature's shape and size. Your equipment doesn't change size or shape to match the new form, and any equipment that the new form can't wear must either fall to the ground or merge with it. Equipment that merges with the form has no effect until you leave the form. </text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<optional>1</optional>
				<name>Primal Strike (Circle of the Moon)</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, your attacks in beast form count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</text>
			</feat>
			<proficiency>3</proficiency>
			<proficiency>4</proficiency>
			<autolevel>
				<slots>2,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Starting Proficiencies</name>
					<text>Armor: light armor, medium armor, shields (druids will not wear armor or use shields made of metal)
	
	Weapons: clubs, daggers, darts, javelins, maces, quarterstaffs, scimitars, sickles, slings, spears
	
	Tools: herbalism kit</text>
					<expanded>0</expanded>
					<proficiency>110</proficiency>
					<proficiency>101</proficiency>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Starting Equipment</name>
					<text>You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.
	
	• (a) a wooden shield or (b) any simple weapon
	• (a) a scimitar or (b) any simple melee weapon
	• Leather armor, an explorer's pack, and a druidic focus
	
	Alternatively, you may start with 2d4 x 10 gp and choose your own equipment.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Druidic</name>
					<text>You know Druidic, the secret language of druids. You can speak the language and use it to leave hidden messages. You and others who know this language automatically spot such a message. Others spot the message's presence with a successful DC 15 Wisdom (Perception) check but can't decipher it without magic.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Spellcasting</name>
					<text>Cantrips:
	At 1st level, you know two cantrips of your choice from the druid spell list. You learn an additional druid cantrip of your choice at 4th level and another at 10th level. 
	
	Preparing and Casting Spells:
	The Druid table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these druid spells, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.
	You prepare the list of druid spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the druid spell list. When you do so, choose a number of druid spells equal to your Wisdom modifier + your druid level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.
	You can also change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of druid spells requires time spent in prayer and meditation: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list. 
	
	Spellcasting Ability:
	Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your druid spells, since your magic draws upon your devotion and attunement to nature. You use your Wisdom whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a druid spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.
	Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier
	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier 
	
	Ritual Casting:
	You can cast a druid spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell prepared. 
	
	Spellcasting Focus:
	You can use a druidic focus (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your druid spells.</text>
					<expanded>0</expanded>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>2</level>
				<slots>2,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Wild Shape</name>
					<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your action to magically assume the shape of a beast that you have seen before. You can use this feature twice. You regain expended uses when you finish a short or long rest.
	Your druid level determines the beasts you can transform into, as shown in the Beast Shapes table (Player's Handbook, p. 66).
	At 2nd level, you can transform into any beast that has a challenge rating of 1/4 or lower that doesn't have a flying or swimming speed.  At 4th level, you can transform into any beast that has a challenge rating of 1/2 or lower that doesn't have a flying speed.  At 8th level, you can transform into any beast that has a challenge rating of 1 or lower.
	You can stay in a beast shape for a number of hours equal to half your druid level (rounded down). You then revert to your normal form unless you expend another use of this feature. You can revert to your normal form earlier by using a bonus action on your turn. You automatically revert if you fall unconscious, drop to 0 hit points, or die.
	While you are transformed, the following rules apply.
	
	• Your game statistics are replaced by the statistics of the beast, but you retain your alignment, personality, and Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma scores. You also retain all of your skill and saving throw proficiencies, in addition to gaining those of the creature. If the creature has the same proficiency as you and the bonus in its stat block is higher than yours, use the creature's bonus instead of yours. If the creature has any legendary or lair actions, you can't use them.
	
	• When you transform, you assume the beast's hit points and Hit Dice. When you revert to your normal form, you return to the number of hit points you had before you transformed. However, if you revert as a result of dropping to 0 hit points, any excess damage carries over to your normal form. For example, if you take 10 damage in animal form and have only 1 hit point left, you revert and take 9 damage. As long as the excess damage doesn't reduce your normal form to 0 hit points, you aren't knocked unconscious.
	
	• You can't cast spells, and your ability to speak or take any action that requires hands is limited to the capabilities of your beast form. Transforming doesn't break your concentration on a spell you've already cast, however, or prevent you from taking actions that are part of a spell, such as call lightning, that you've already cast.
	
	• You retain the benefit of any features from your class, race, or other source and can use them if the new form is physically capable of doing so. However, you can't use any of your special senses, such as darkvision, unless your new form also has that sense.
	
	• You choose whether your equipment falls to the ground in your space, merges into your new form, or is worn by it. Worn equipment functions as normal, but the DM decides whether it is practical for the new form to wear a piece of equipment, based on the creature's shape and size. Your equipment doesn't change size or shape to match the new form, and any equipment that the new form can't wear must either fall to the ground or merge with it. Equipment that merges with the form has no effect until you leave the form. </text>
					<expanded>0</expanded>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Druid Circle</name>
					<text>At 2nd level, you choose to identify with a circle of druids: the Circle of the Land or the Circle of the Moon, both detailed at the end of the class description. Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Circle of the Land</name>
					<text>Circle of the Land:
	The Circle of the Land is made up of mystics and sages who safeguard ancient knowledge and rites through a vast oral tradition. These druids meet within sacred circles of trees or standing stones to whisper primal secrets in Druidic. The circle's wisest members preside as the chief priests of communities that hold to the Old Faith and serve as advisors to the rulers of those folk. As a member of this circle, your magic is influenced by the land where you were initiated into the circle's mysterious rites.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Bonus Cantrip (Circle of the Land)</name>
					<text>When you choose this domain at 1st level, you gain the light cantrip if you don't already know it.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Natural Recovery (Circle of the Land)</name>
					<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can regain some of your magical energy by sitting in meditation and communing with nature. During a short rest, you choose expended spell slots to recover. The spell slots can have a combined level that is equal to or less than half your druid level (rounded up), and none of the slots can be 6th level or higher. You can't use this feature again until you finish a long rest
	For example, when you are a 4th-level druid, you can recover up to two levels worth of spell slots. You can recover either a 2nd-level slot or two 1st-level slots.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Circle of the Moon</name>
					<text>Druids of the Circle of the Moon are fierce guardians of the wilds. Their order gathers under the full moon to share news and trade warnings. They haunt the deepest parts of the wilderness, where they might go for weeks on end before crossing paths with another humanoid creature, let alone another druid.
	Changeable as the moon, a druid of this circle might prowl as a great cat one night, soar over the treetops as an eagle the next day, and crash through the undergrowth in bear form to drive off a trespassing monster. The wild is in the druid's blood.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Combat Wild Shape (Circle of the Moon)</name>
					<text>When you choose this circle at 2nd level, you gain the ability to use Wild Shape on your turn as a bonus action, rather than as an action.
	Additionally, while you are transformed by Wild Shape, you can use a bonus action to expend one spell slot to regain 1d8 hit points per level of the spell slot expended.</text>
					<expanded>0</expanded>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Circle Forms (Circle of the Moon)</name>
					<text>The rites of your circle grant you the ability to transform into more dangerous animal forms. Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Wild Shape to transform into a beast with a challenge rating as high as 1 (you ignore the Max. CR column of the Beast Shapes table, but must abide by the other limitations there).
	Starting at 6th level, you can transform into a beast with a challenge rating as high as your druid level divided by 3, rounded down.</text>
					<expanded>0</expanded>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>3</level>
				<slots>2,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Circle Spells (Circle of the Land)</name>
					<text>Your mystical connection to the land infuses you with the ability to cast certain spells. At 3rd, 5th, 7th, and 9th level you gain access to circle spells connected to the land where you became a druid. Choose that land — arctic, coast, desert, forest, grassland, mountain, swamp, or Underdark — and consult the associated list of spells.
	Once you gain access to a circle spell, you always have it prepared, and it doesn't count against the number of spells you can prepare each day. If you gain access to a spell that doesn't appear on the druid spell list, the spell is nonetheless a druid spell for you.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Circle of the Land: Arctic</name>
					<text>At each indicated level, add the listed spells to your druid spell list.  These spells are always prepared and don't count against the number of spells you prepare wach day.
	
	3rd — hold person, spike growth
	5th — sleet storm, slow 
	7th — freedom of movement, ice storm 
	9th — commune with nature, cone of cold</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Circle of the Land: Coast</name>
					<text>At each indicated level, add the listed spells to your druid spell list.  These spells are always prepared and don't count against the number of spells you prepare wach day.
	
	3rd—  mirror image, misty step 
	5th — water breathing, water walk 
	7th — control water, freedom of movement 
	9th — conjure elemental, scrying</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Circle of the Land: Desert</name>
					<text>At each indicated level, add the listed spells to your druid spell list.  These spells are always prepared and don't count against the number of spells you prepare wach day.
	
	3rd — blur, silence 
	5th — create food and water, protection from energy 
	7th — blight, hallucinatory terrain 
	9th — insect plague, wall of stone</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Circle of the Land: Forest</name>
					<text>At each indicated level, add the listed spells to your druid spell list.  These spells are always prepared and don't count against the number of spells you prepare wach day.
	
	3rd — barkskin, spider climb 
	5th — call lightning, plant growth 
	7th — divination, freedom of movement 
	9th — commune with nature, tree stride</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Circle of the Land: Grassland</name>
					<text>At each indicated level, add the listed spells to your druid spell list.  These spells are always prepared and don't count against the number of spells you prepare wach day.
	
	3rd — invisibility, pass without trace 
	5th — daylight, haste 
	7th — divination, freedom of movement 
	9th — dream, insect plague</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Circle of the Land: Mountain</name>
					<text>At each indicated level, add the listed spells to your druid spell list.  These spells are always prepared and don't count against the number of spells you prepare wach day.
	
	3rd — spider climb, spike growth 
	5th — lightning bolt, meld into stone 
	7th — stone shape, stoneskin 
	9th — passwall, wall of stone</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Circle of the Land: Swamp</name>
					<text>At each indicated level, add the listed spells to your druid spell list.  These spells are always prepared and don't count against the number of spells you prepare wach day.
	
	3rd — darkness, Melf's acid arrow
	5th — water walk, stinking cloud
	7th — freedom of movement, locate creature
	9th — insect plague, scrying</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Circle of the Land: Underdark</name>
					<text>At each indicated level, add the listed spells to your druid spell list.  These spells are always prepared and don't count against the number of spells you prepare wach day.
	
	3rd — spider climb, web 
	5th — gaseous form, stinking cloud 
	7th — greater invisibility, stone shape 
	9th — cloudkill, insect plague</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>4</level>
				<slots>3,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
					<text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>5</level>
				<slots>3,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>6</level>
				<slots>3,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Nature's Stride (Circle of the Land)</name>
					<text>Starting at 6th level, moving through nonmagical difficult terrain costs you no extra movement. You can also pass through nonmagical plants without being slowed by them and without taking damage from them if they have thorns, spines, or a similar hazard.
	In addition, you have advantage on saving throws against plants that are magically created or manipulated to impede movement, such those created by the entangle spell.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Primal Strike (Circle of the Moon)</name>
					<text>Starting at 6th level, your attacks in beast form count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>7</level>
				<slots>3,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>8</level>
				<slots>3,4,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>9</level>
				<slots>3,4,3,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>10</level>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Nature's Ward (Circle of the Land)</name>
					<text>When you reach 10th level, you can't be charmed or frightened by elementals or fey, and you are immune to poison and disease.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Elemental Wild Shape (Circle of the Moon)</name>
					<text>At 10th level, you can expend two uses of Wild Shape at the same time to transform into an air elemental, an earth elemental, a fire elemental, or a water elemental.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>11</level>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>12</level>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>13</level>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>14</level>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Nature's Sanctuary (Circle of the Land)</name>
					<text>When you reach 14th level, creatures of the natural world sense your connection to nature and become hesitant to attack you. When a beast or plant creature attacks you, that creature must make a Wisdom saving throw against your druid spell save DC. On a failed save, the creature must choose a different target, or the attack automatically misses. On a successful save, the creature is immune to this effect for 24 hours.
	The creature is aware of this effect before it makes its attack against you.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Thousand Forms (Circle of the Moon)</name>
					<text>By 14th level, you have learned to use magic to alter your physical form in more subtle ways. You can cast the alter self spell at will.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>15</level>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>16</level>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>17</level>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,1,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>18</level>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,3,3,1,1,1,1,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Timeless Body</name>
					<text>Starting at 18th level, the primal magic that you wield causes you to age more slowly. For every 10 years that pass, your body ages only 1 year.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Beast Spells</name>
					<text>Beginning at 18th level, you can cast many of your druid spells in any shape you assume using Wild Shape. You can perform the somatic and verbal components of a druid spell while in a beast shape, but you aren't able to provide material components.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>19</level>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>20</level>
				<spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,3,3,2,2,1,1,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Archdruid</name>
					<text>At 20th level, you can use your Wild Shape an unlimited number of times.
	Additionally, you can ignore the verbal and somatic components of your druid spells, as well as any material components that lack a cost and aren't consumed by a spell. You gain this benefit in both your normal shape and your beast shape from Wild Shape.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
		</class>
		<background>
			<id>9</id>
			<name>Hermit</name>
			<feat>
				<name>Discovery</name>
				<text>The quiet seclusion of your extended hermitage gave you access to a unique and powerful discovery. The exact nature of this revelation depends on the nature of your seclusion. It might be a great truth about the cosmos, the deities, the powerful beings of the outer planes, or the forces of nature. It could be a site that no one else has ever seen. You might have uncovered a fact that has long been forgotten, or unearthed some relic of the past that could rewrite history. It might be information that would be damaging to the people who or consigned you to exile, and hence the reason for your return to society.
Work with your DM to determine the details of your discovery and its impact on the campaign.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Life of Seclusion</name>
				<text>I retreated from society after a life-altering event.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Personality Trait</name>
				<text>I am oblivious to etiquette and social expectations.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Ideal</name>
				<text>Free Thinking: Inquiry and curiosity are the pillars of progress.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Bond</name>
				<text>I'm still seeking the enlightenment that I pursued in my seclusion and it still eludes me.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Flaw</name>
				<text>I'd risk too much to uncover a lost bit of knowledge.</text>
			</feat>
			<proficiency>114</proficiency>
			<proficiency>109</proficiency>
		</background>
		<xp>7775</xp>
		<abilities>10,13,10,13,17,10,</abilities>
		<hpMax>33</hpMax>
		<hpCurrent>18</hpCurrent>
		<hpTemp>60</hpTemp>
		<feat>
			<name>Alert</name>
			<text>Always on the lookout for danger, you gain the following 

• You gain a +5 bonus to initiative.

• You can't be surprised while you are conscious.

• Other creatures don't gain advantage on attack rolls against you as a result of being hidden from you.</text>
			<mod>
				<type>12</type>
				<value>5</value>
			</mod>
		</feat>
		<item>
			<name>Wand of Magic Missiles</name>
			<text>Rarity: Uncommon
This wand has 7 charges. While holding it, you can use an action to expend 1 or more of its charges to cast the magic missile spell from it. For 1 charge, you cast the 1st-level version of the spell. You can increase the spell slot level by one for each additional charge you expend.
The wand regains 1d6+1 expended charges daily at dawn. If you expend the wand's last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the wand crumbles into ashes and is destroyed.

Source: Dungeon Master's Guide p. 211</text>
			<type>10</type>
			<weight>1</weight>
			<roll>1d6+1</roll>
			<roll>(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)</roll>
			<roll>(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)</roll>
			<roll>(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)</roll>
			<roll>(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)</roll>
			<roll>(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)</roll>
			<roll>(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)</roll>
			<roll>(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)+(1d4+1)</roll>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Quarterstaff</name>
			<text>Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property — the damage when the weapon is used with two hands to make a melee attack.

Cost: 2 sp

Source: Player's Handbook p. 149</text>
			<type>5</type>
			<slot>2</slot>
			<weight>4</weight>
			<damage1H>1d6</damage1H>
			<damage2H>1d8</damage2H>
			<damageType>1</damageType>
			<weaponProperty>512</weaponProperty>
			<mod>
				<type>1</type>
			</mod>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Sling</name>
			<text>Ammunition: You can use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a ranged attack only if you have ammunition to fire from the weapon. Each time you attack with the weapon, you expend one piece of ammunition. Drawing the ammunition from a quiver, case, or other container is part of the attack. Loading a one-handed weapon requires a free hand. At the end of the battle, you can recover half your expended ammunition by taking a minute to search the battlefield.
If you use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a melee attack, you treat the weapon as an improvised weapon. A sling must be loaded to deal any damage when used in this way.

Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.

Cost: 1 sp

Source: Player's Handbook p. 149</text>
			<type>6</type>
			<weight>0</weight>
			<damage1H>1d4</damage1H>
			<damageType>1</damageType>
			<weaponProperty>1</weaponProperty>
			<weaponRange>30</weaponRange>
			<weaponLongRange>120</weaponLongRange>
			<mod>
				<type>1</type>
			</mod>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Studded Leather Armor</name>
			<text>Made from tough but flexible leather, studded leather is reinforced with close-set rivets or spikes.

Cost: 45 gp

Source: Player's Handbook p. 144</text>
			<type>1</type>
			<slot>5</slot>
			<weight>13</weight>
			<ac>12</ac>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Explorer's Pack</name>
			<text>Includes:
• a backpack
• a bedroll
• a mess kit
• a tinderbox
• 10 torches
• 10 days of rations
• a waterskin
• 50 feet of hempen rope

Cost: 10 gp

Source: Player's Handbook p. 151</text>
			<weight>59</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Gold (gp)</name>
			<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).
With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don't usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.
One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer's work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night's rest in a poor inn.
One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.
In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.
A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player's Handbook p. 143</text>
			<type>15</type>
			<quantity>164</quantity>
			<weight>0.02</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Healer's Kit</name>
			<text>This kit is a leather pouch containing bandages, salves, and splints. The kit has ten uses. As an action, you can expend one use of the kit to stabilize a creature that has 0 hit points, without needing to make a Wisdom (Medicine) check.

Cost: 5 gp

Source: Player's Handbook p. 151</text>
			<weight>3</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Herbalism Kit</name>
			<text>This kit contains a variety of instruments such as clippers, mortar and pestle, and pouches and vials used by herbalists to create remedies and potions. Proficiency with this kit lets you add your proficiency bonus to any ability checks you make to identify or apply herbs. Also, proficiency with this kit is required to create antitoxin and potions of healing.

Cost: 5 gp

Source: Player's Handbook p. 154</text>
			<slot>1</slot>
			<weight>3</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Druidic Focus</name>
			<text>A bear's tooth necklace. A Druid can use this as a spellcasting focus.</text>
			<slot>1</slot>
			<weight>0</weight>
		</item>
		<tracker>
			<label>Wild Shape</label>
			<resetType>1</resetType>
			<value>2</value>
			<formula>2</formula>
		</tracker>
		<tracker>
			<label>Wand of Magic Missiles</label>
			<formula>7</formula>
		</tracker>
		<monster>
			<name>Giant Elk</name>
			<size>4</size>
			<type>beast</type>
			<alignment>unaligned</alignment>
			<ac>15</ac>
			<armor>natural armor</armor>
			<hpMax>42</hpMax>
			<hpCurrent>42</hpCurrent>
			<speed>60 ft.</speed>
			<abilities>19,16,14,7,14,10,</abilities>
			<skill>
				<id>11</id>
				<modifier>4</modifier>
			</skill>
			<passive>14</passive>
			<languages>Giant Elk, understands Common, Elvish, and Sylvan but can't speak</languages>
			<cr>2</cr>
			<trait>
				<name>Charge</name>
				<text>If the elk moves at least 20 ft. straight toward a target and then hits it with a ram attack on the same turn, the target takes an extra 7 (2d6) damage. If the target is a creature, it must succeed on a DC 14 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone.</text>
				<attack>
					<name>Charge</name>
					<damage>2d6</damage>
				</attack>
			</trait>
			<action>
				<name>Ram</name>
				<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 11 (2d6+4) bludgeoning damage.</text>
				<attack>
					<name>Ram</name>
					<attackBonus>6</attackBonus>
					<damage>2d6+4</damage>
				</attack>
			</action>
			<action>
				<name>Hooves</name>
				<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one prone creature. Hit: 22 (4d8+4) bludgeoning damage.</text>
				<attack>
					<name>Hooves</name>
					<attackBonus>6</attackBonus>
					<damage>4d8+4</damage>
				</attack>
			</action>
		</monster>
		<monster>
			<name>Giant Constrictor Snake</name>
			<size>4</size>
			<type>beast</type>
			<alignment>unaligned</alignment>
			<ac>12</ac>
			<hpMax>60</hpMax>
			<hpCurrent>60</hpCurrent>
			<speed>30 ft., swim 30 ft.</speed>
			<abilities>19,14,12,1,10,3,</abilities>
			<skill>
				<id>11</id>
				<modifier>2</modifier>
			</skill>
			<senses>blindsight 10 ft.</senses>
			<passive>12</passive>
			<cr>2</cr>
			<action>
				<name>Bite</name>
				<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 10 ft., one creature. Hit: 11 (2d6+4) piercing damage.</text>
				<attack>
					<name>Bite</name>
					<attackBonus>6</attackBonus>
					<damage>2d6+4</damage>
				</attack>
			</action>
			<action>
				<name>Constrict</name>
				<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: 13 (2d8+4) bludgeoning damage, and the target is grappled (escape DC 16). Until this grapple ends, the creature is restrained, and the snake can't constrict another target.

Grappled:
• A grappled creature's speed becomes 0, and it can't benefit from any bonus to its speed.

• The condition ends if the grappler is incapacitated.

• The condition also ends if an effect removes the grappled creature from the reach of the grappler or grappling effect, such as when a creature is hurled away by the thunderwave spell.

Restrained:
• A restrained creature's speed becomes 0, and it can't benefit from any bonus to its speed.

• Attack rolls against the creature have advantage, and the creature's attack rolls have disadvantage.

• The creature has disadvantage on Dexterity saving throws.</text>
				<attack>
					<name>Constrict</name>
					<attackBonus>6</attackBonus>
					<damage>2d8+4</damage>
				</attack>
			</action>
		</monster>
		<monster>
			<name>Brown Bear</name>
			<size>3</size>
			<type>beast</type>
			<alignment>unaligned</alignment>
			<ac>11</ac>
			<armor>natural armor</armor>
			<hpMax>34</hpMax>
			<hpCurrent>34</hpCurrent>
			<speed>40 ft., climb 30 ft.</speed>
			<abilities>19,10,16,2,13,7,</abilities>
			<skill>
				<id>11</id>
				<modifier>3</modifier>
			</skill>
			<passive>13</passive>
			<trait>
				<name>Keen Smell</name>
				<text>The bear has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell.</text>
			</trait>
			<action>
				<name>Multiattack</name>
				<text>The bear makes two attacks: one with its bite and one with its claws.</text>
			</action>
			<action>
				<name>Bite</name>
				<text>Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 8 (1d8+4) piercing damage.</text>
				<attack>
					<name>Bite</name>
					<attackBonus>5</attackBonus>
					<damage>1d8+4</damage>
				</attack>
			</action>
			<action>
				<name>Claws</name>
				<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 11 (2d6+4) slashing damage.</text>
				<attack>
					<name>Claws</name>
					<attackBonus>5</attackBonus>
					<damage>2d6+4</damage>
				</attack>
			</action>
		</monster>
		<monster>
			<name>Giant Spider</name>
			<size>3</size>
			<type>beast</type>
			<alignment>unaligned</alignment>
			<ac>14</ac>
			<armor>natural armor</armor>
			<hpMax>26</hpMax>
			<hpCurrent>26</hpCurrent>
			<speed>30 ft., climb 30 ft.</speed>
			<abilities>14,16,12,2,11,4,</abilities>
			<skill>
				<id>16</id>
				<modifier>7</modifier>
			</skill>
			<senses>blindsight 10 ft., darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
			<trait>
				<name>Spider Climb</name>
				<text>The spider can climb difficult surfaces, including upside down on ceilings, without needing to make an ability check.</text>
			</trait>
			<trait>
				<name>Web Sense</name>
				<text>While in contact with a web, the spider knows the exact location of any other creature in contact with the same web.</text>
			</trait>
			<trait>
				<name>Web Walker</name>
				<text>The spider ignores movement restrictions caused by webbing.</text>
			</trait>
			<action>
				<name>Bite</name>
				<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: 7 (1d8+3) piercing damage, and the target must make a DC 11 Constitution saving throw, taking 9 (2d8) poison damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. If the poison damage reduces the target to 0 hit points, the target is stable but poisoned for 1 hour, even after regaining hit points, and is paralyzed while poisoned in this way.

Paralyzed:
• A paralyzed creature is incapacitated, meaning it can't take actions or reactions, and can't move or speak.

• The creature automatically fails Strength and Dexterity saving throws.

• Attack rolls against the creature have advantage.

• Any attack that hits the creature is a critical hit if the attacker is within 5 feet of the creature.

Poisoned:
• A poisoned creature has disadvantage on attack rolls and ability checks.</text>
				<attack>
					<name>Bite</name>
					<attackBonus>5</attackBonus>
					<damage>1d8+3</damage>
				</attack>
			</action>
			<action>
				<name>Web (Recharge 5-6)</name>
				<text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, range 30/60 ft., one creature. Hit: The target is restrained by webbing. As an action, the restrained target can make a DC 12 Strength check, bursting the webbing on a success. The webbing can also be attacked and destroyed (AC 10; hp 5; vulnerability to fire damage; immunity to bludgeoning, poison, and psychic damage).

Restrained:
• A restrained creature's speed becomes 0, and it can't benefit from any bonus to its speed.

• Attack rolls against the creature have advantage, and the creature's attack rolls have disadvantage.

• The creature has disadvantage on Dexterity saving throws.</text>
				<attack>
					<name>Web</name>
					<attackBonus>5</attackBonus>
					<damage>0</damage>
				</attack>
			</action>
		</monster>
		<monster>
			<name>Giant Frog</name>
			<type>beast</type>
			<alignment>unaligned</alignment>
			<ac>11</ac>
			<hpMax>18</hpMax>
			<hpCurrent>18</hpCurrent>
			<speed>30 ft., swim 30 ft.</speed>
			<abilities>12,13,11,2,10,3,</abilities>
			<skill>
				<id>11</id>
				<modifier>2</modifier>
			</skill>
			<skill>
				<id>16</id>
				<modifier>3</modifier>
			</skill>
			<senses>darkvision 30 ft.</senses>
			<passive>12</passive>
			<cr>-1</cr>
			<trait>
				<name>Amphibious</name>
				<text>The frog can breathe air and water</text>
			</trait>
			<trait>
				<name>Standing Leap</name>
				<text>The frog's long jump is up to 20 ft. and its high jump is up to 10 ft., with or without a running start.</text>
			</trait>
			<action>
				<name>Bite</name>
				<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d6+1) piercing damage, and the target is grappled (escape DC 11). Until this grapple ends, the target is restrained, and the frog can't bite another target.

Grappled:
• A grappled creature's speed becomes 0, and it can't benefit from any bonus to its speed.

• The condition ends if the grappler is incapacitated.

• The condition also ends if an effect removes the grappled creature from the reach of the grappler or grappling effect, such as when a creature is hurled away by the thunderwave spell.

Restrained:
• A restrained creature's speed becomes 0, and it can't benefit from any bonus to its speed.

• Attack rolls against the creature have advantage, and the creature's attack rolls have disadvantage.

• The creature has disadvantage on Dexterity saving throws.</text>
				<attack>
					<name>Bite</name>
					<attackBonus>3</attackBonus>
					<damage>1d6+1</damage>
				</attack>
			</action>
			<action>
				<name>Swallow</name>
				<text>The frog makes one bite attack against a Small or smaller target it is grappling. If the attack hits, the target is swallowed, and the grapple ends. The swallowed target is blinded and restrained, it has total cover against attacks and other effects outside the frog, and it takes 5 (2d4) acid damage at the start of each of the frog's turns. The frog can have only one target swallowed at a time. If the frog dies, a swallowed creature is no longer restrained by it and can escape from the corpse using 5 ft. of movement, exiting prone.

Blinded:
• A blinded creature can't see and automatically fails any ability check that requires sight.

• Attack rolls against the creature have advantage, and the creature's attack rolls have disadvantage.

Prone:
• A prone creature's only movement option is to crawl, unless it stands up and thereby ends the condition.

• The creature has disadvantage on attack rolls.

• An attack roll against the creature has advantage if the attacker is within 5 feet of the creature. Otherwise, the attack roll has disadvantage.

Restrained:
• A restrained creature's speed becomes 0, and it can't benefit from any bonus to its speed.

• Attack rolls against the creature have advantage, and the creature's attack rolls have disadvantage.

• The creature has disadvantage on Dexterity saving throws.</text>
			</action>
		</monster>
		<monster>
			<name>Weasel</name>
			<size>0</size>
			<type>beast</type>
			<alignment>unaligned</alignment>
			<ac>13</ac>
			<hpMax>1</hpMax>
			<hpCurrent>1</hpCurrent>
			<speed>30 ft.</speed>
			<abilities>3,16,8,2,12,3,</abilities>
			<skill>
				<id>11</id>
				<modifier>3</modifier>
			</skill>
			<skill>
				<id>16</id>
				<modifier>5</modifier>
			</skill>
			<passive>13</passive>
			<cr>-3</cr>
			<trait>
				<name>Keen Hearing and Smell</name>
				<text>The weasel has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or smell.</text>
			</trait>
			<action>
				<name>Bite</name>
				<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: 1 piercing damage.</text>
				<attack>
					<name>Bite</name>
					<attackBonus>5</attackBonus>
					<damage>1</damage>
				</attack>
			</action>
		</monster>
		<monster>
			<name>Wolf</name>
			<type>beast</type>
			<alignment>unaligned</alignment>
			<ac>13</ac>
			<armor>natural armor</armor>
			<hpMax>11</hpMax>
			<hpCurrent>11</hpCurrent>
			<speed>40 ft.</speed>
			<abilities>12,15,12,3,12,6,</abilities>
			<skill>
				<id>11</id>
				<modifier>3</modifier>
			</skill>
			<skill>
				<id>16</id>
				<modifier>4</modifier>
			</skill>
			<passive>13</passive>
			<cr>-1</cr>
			<trait>
				<name>Keen Hearing and Smell</name>
				<text>The wolf has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or smell.</text>
			</trait>
			<trait>
				<name>Pack Tactics</name>
				<text>The wolf has advantage on an attack roll against a creature if at least one of the wolf's allies is within 5 ft. of the creature and the ally isn't incapacitated.</text>
			</trait>
			<action>
				<name>Bite</name>
				<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 7 (2d4+2) piercing damage. If the target is a creature, it must succeed on a DC 11 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone.

Prone:
• A prone creature's only movement option is to crawl, unless it stands up and thereby ends the condition.

• The creature has disadvantage on attack rolls.

• An attack roll against the creature has advantage if the attacker is within 5 feet of the creature. Otherwise, the attack roll has disadvantage.</text>
				<attack>
					<name>Bite</name>
					<attackBonus>4</attackBonus>
					<damage>2d4+2</damage>
				</attack>
			</action>
		</monster>
		<monster>
			<name>Panther</name>
			<type>beast</type>
			<alignment>unaligned</alignment>
			<ac>12</ac>
			<hpMax>13</hpMax>
			<hpCurrent>13</hpCurrent>
			<speed>50 ft., climb 40 ft.</speed>
			<abilities>14,15,10,3,14,7,</abilities>
			<skill>
				<id>11</id>
				<modifier>4</modifier>
			</skill>
			<skill>
				<id>16</id>
				<modifier>6</modifier>
			</skill>
			<passive>14</passive>
			<cr>-1</cr>
			<trait>
				<name>Keen Smell</name>
				<text>The panther has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell.</text>
			</trait>
			<trait>
				<name>Pounce</name>
				<text>If the panther moves at least 20 ft. straight toward a creature and then hits it with a claw attack on the same turn, that target must succeed on a DC 12 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone. If the target is prone, the panther can make one bite attack against it as a bonus action.</text>
			</trait>
			<action>
				<name>Bite</name>
				<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d6+2) piercing damage.</text>
				<attack>
					<name>Bite</name>
					<attackBonus>4</attackBonus>
					<damage>1d6+2</damage>
				</attack>
			</action>
			<action>
				<name>Claw</name>
				<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d4+2) slashing damage.</text>
				<attack>
					<name>Claw</name>
					<attackBonus>4</attackBonus>
					<damage>1d4+2</damage>
				</attack>
			</action>
		</monster>
		<imageData>
			<uniqueID>1182</uniqueID>
		</imageData>
	</character>
</pc>